<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Quick &amp; easy &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/quick-easy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 06:44:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Crunchy mixed greens with mustard vinaigrette</title>
		<link>/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 01:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px"><em>"There might not be enough food... the boys are coming and&#160;they eat A LOT"</em> -&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">Lil' Sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch. Despite being fairly confident that&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">there would be plenty of food</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;I agreed to add an extra dish,</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;opting</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&#160;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&#160;(Admittedly&#160;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&#160;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&#160;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img-5.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<figure>
<blockquote><p>
    <span>&#8220;</span>There might not be enough food&#8230; the boys are coming and they eat A LOT.<span>&#8221;</span><br />
  </blockquote><figcaption class="source">&mdash; Lil&#8217; sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite being fairly confident that&nbsp;there would be plenty of food&nbsp;I agreed to add an extra dish,&nbsp;opting&nbsp;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&nbsp;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&nbsp;(Admittedly&nbsp;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&nbsp;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&nbsp;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</p>
<p>Back home and through the process of testing the recipe this salad&nbsp;has rapidly become a favourite. Only thing is, there are two versions and I can&#8217;t decide which I like best, so I&#8217;ve included both options and you can choose for yourself.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The question before you is this: pomegranate or cranberries? The pomegranate seeds are refreshing and add a nice crunch. The cranberries are sweeter and slightly chewy. I like both versions. I&#8217;d suggest the pomegranate&nbsp;as a nice refreshing choice&nbsp;on a&nbsp;warm day, and the cranberries when you&#8217;re looking to bring a little more sweetness to the meal. Dried cranberries are also typically easier to come by than fresh pomegranates.</p>
<p>I haven&#8217;t included rocket in my leafy greens.&nbsp;Personally I don&#8217;t like rocket&nbsp;&#8211;&nbsp;I find it too hot &#8211;&nbsp;while the watercress here is just a little peppery.&nbsp;If you are a fan of rocket&nbsp;I suspect if would work well in this salad, and I always encourage experimentation when cooking.</p>
<p>For a nut free version, skip the almonds. It won&#8217;t be as crunchy but the combination of flavours should still survive. For a vegan or dairy/lactose-free alternative, omit the parmesan.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 cups baby kale</li>
<li>2 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>1 cup watercress leaves, removed from stems</li>
<li>½ cup almonds</li>
<li>1 pomegranate or ½ cup dried cranberries</li>
<li>½ cup shaved parmesan</li>
<li>½ red onion, finely sliced or diced</li>
<li><a href="#">⅓ cup mustard Vinaigrette (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If using a&nbsp;pomegranate, start by seeding the fruit (otherwise, skip straight to the next paragraph). Tori&nbsp;Avey provides some great instructions explaining&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://toriavey.com/toris-kitchen/2011/09/how-to-seed-a-pomegranate/#recipe">How to Seed a Pomegranate</a>. (Tori&#8217;s post also includes instructions for juicing a pomegranate &#8211; don&#8217;t go that far here, for this salad you want to keep the seeds whole.)</p>
<p>Place kale, spinach and&nbsp;watercress&nbsp;in a large salad bowl and toss to mix. Pour mustard vinaigrette over the top&nbsp;and toss again so the greens are well coated with&nbsp;the dressing. Add the almonds, pomegranate or cranberries, parmesan and onion. Toss to combine all ingredients and serve straight away.</p>
<p><a name="mustardvinaigrette"></a></p>
<p><strong>Mustard Vinaigrette</strong></p>
<p>Makes a little over&nbsp;⅓ cup</p>
<ul>
<li>½ lemon, juiced (around 1½ tablespoons lemon juice)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dijon mustard</li>
<li>2 teaspoons white wine vinegar</li>
<li>¼ cup olive oil</li>
<li>pinch each of&nbsp;salt and pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar,&nbsp;(ensure the lid is properly secured,)&nbsp;and shake well to combine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snickers bar smoothie</title>
		<link>/2014/12/09/2014-12-9-snickers-bar-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 06:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet treats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/12/09/2014-12-9-snickers-bar-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>Deliciousness in a glass! I mean seriously, who needs junk food when you can make treats like this that are made with proper&#160;food and contain real nutrients while also making your taste buds super happy?!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/img-2.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Deliciousness in a glass! I mean seriously, who needs junk food when you can make treats like this that are made with proper&nbsp;food and contain real nutrients while also making your taste buds super happy?!</p>
<p>For vegan and dairy/lactose free alternatives, use soy or other non-dairy&nbsp;milk and either skip the yoghurt or try replacing it with silken tofu or non-dairy yoghurt.</p>
<p>Serves 1</p>
<ul>
<li>1 banana, peeled and cut into chunks</li>
<li>¼ cup skim milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons peanut butter</li>
<li>2 tablespoons natural yoghurt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cocoa powder</li>
<li>½ cup ice blocks (adjust depending on how cold you&#8217;d like your smoothie, alternatively use frozen banana and skip the ice).</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citrus chia &#8216;frogs eggs&#8217;</title>
		<link>/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 23:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p><p><span style="font-size:15px">This snack idea is so simple I almost didn't post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I've had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.</span><span style="font-size:15px">&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Chiagoupeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p>
<p>This snack idea is so simple I almost didn&#8217;t post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I&#8217;ve had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.</p>
<p>I particularly like chia prepared this way because it&#8217;s an energy source that&#8217;s light enough that I can drink it then proceed to exercise 15 minutes later without feeling remotely ill &#8211; even if that exercise is teaching Body Attack with it&#8217;s tuck-jump-burpees. There are not many foods for which I can say the same.</p>
<p>Now for the credits: idea courtesy of my sister, and the name&#8230; inspired by my mother who came close to convincing her squad of swimmers,&nbsp;using post-exercise nutritional arguments,&nbsp;that she was in fact drinking frogs eggs!</p>
<p>Serves 1</p>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds (any colour)</li>
<li>juice of half a lemon or lime (if you like stronger citrus flavours, add juice from the whole fruit)</li>
<li>300mL water</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar. Secure lid and shake well. Shake a couple of times over the next 5-10 minutes so the chia doesn&#8217;t clump together too densely. Refrigerate or allow to sit for at least 30 minutes and you&#8217;re done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; herb cornbread</title>
		<link>/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 03:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who's had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn't want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That's where this cornbread comes in.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/cornbread_edited_compressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who&#8217;s had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn&#8217;t want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That&#8217;s where this cornbread comes in. I have lost track of the number of times I&#8217;ve read an introduction to a recipe for gluten-free baked goods along the lines of &#8220;while other gluten-free recipes may turn out too dense, dry and crumbly or tasting of cardboard, this one actually works!&#8221; only to discover that no, that recipe did not work and was in fact so bad the result ended up in the bin. Again. Hence my delight (bordering on astonishment) when this one did actually work! And it&#8217;s really good! So good that my non-coeliac partner will choose this over his (glutenated) toast, when I&#8217;m willing to share.</p>
<p>The recipe is based on one out of The Australian Coeliac, the magazine produced by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/index.html">Coeliac Australia</a>, which I&#8217;ve modified to suit my tastes, namely by using more fresh herbs, less sugar.</p>
<p>Serves 6-8 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>scant cup gluten-free flour*</li>
<li>1/3 cup polenta</li>
<li>1 teaspoon xanthum gum</li>
<li>1 tablespoon caster sugar</li>
<li>1 tablespoon gluten-free baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 cup milk</li>
<li>1 egg, lightly beaten</li>
<li>2 tablespoons canola oil</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly grated parmesan cheese</li>
<li>2/3 cup freshly grated cheddar cheese</li>
<li>6 shallots, finely sliced</li>
<li>1/4 cup fresh herbs, finely chopped (I usually use parsley with one or two others such as basil or thyme, depending on what I have on hand and what soup I&#8217;m making)</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>*I use the brown rice gluten-free flour mix suggested in&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gluten-Free-Baking-Classics-Annalise-Roberts/dp/1572840994%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1572840994">Gluten-Free Baking Classics</a>,</em><span>&nbsp;by Annalise Roberts: 6 parts brown rice flour : 2 parts potato starch : 1 part tapioca starch.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Preheat oven to 220˚C (425 F). Grease a 20cm square baking tin.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Combine dry ingredients (flour, polenta, xanthum gum, sugar, baking powder, salt and pepper) in a large mixing bowl and mix well.</p>
<p>In a separate bowl, whisk together the wet ingredients (milk, egg and canola oil).</p>
<p>Add wet ingredients to the dry and whisk until a smooth batter is formed. Stir in the cheeses, shallots and herbs until just combined.</p>
<p>Pour into baking tin and bake for about 25 minutes, until top is golden and a skewer comes out clean. Check the cornbread after around 15-20 minutes &#8211; if the top is golden and you want to prevent it darkening further while the cornbread cooks through, cover the pan with foil, pricked in a few places to let out excess steam.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Allow to cool in the pan, and serve warm or at room temperature.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ricotta-stuffed mushrooms</title>
		<link>/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 03:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hors d'oeuvres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>If you're in Australia at the moment, chances are you've got a barbecue or three coming up. If you're in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Ricottastuffedmushroomseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re in Australia at the moment, chances are you&#8217;ve got a barbecue or three coming up. If you&#8217;re in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</p>
<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been using largish button mushrooms in this recipe, as they&#8217;re the perfect size for sharing.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re after meal-sized servings though, try using portobello mushrooms instead.</p>
<p>These mushrooms can be baked, grilled or barbecued &#8211; the preparation is all the same.</p>
<p>For a super-quick variant, just mix the ricotta and sun-dried tomatoes with salt and pepper to taste, perhaps add some dry herbs if they&#8217;re handy, pile on top of portobello mushrooms and add to the barbie.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts.</p>
<p>Makes 12 pieces</p>
<p>12 medium-large button mushrooms (or 3-4 portobello mushrooms)</p>
<p>2 cloves garlic, finely chopped</p>
<p>1 tablespoon olive oil</p>
<p>300g ricotta</p>
<p>1/4 cup sun-dried tomatoes, drained and chopped</p>
<p>2 tablespoons pine nuts, toasted</p>
<p>2 tablespoons fresh oregano and/or thyme leaves, finely chopped</p>
<p>salt and pepper</p>
<p>If baking, preheat oven to 180˚C (350F).</p>
<p>Remove stems from the mushrooms and coarsely chop, discarding any woody bits. To remove the stem of a mushroom: hold the mushroom in one hand and use your other hand to pinch the stem, squeezing so the stem splits. Pinch the two halves of the stem together and squeeze so it&#8217;s now split into four pieces. Now twist the stem, and it should come easily away from the mushroom.</p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a small skillet over medium heat. Add mushroom stems and garlic and sauté until garlic is fragrant and stems are lightly browned.</p>
<p>Wrap ricotta in paper towels or cheese cloth and squeeze to remove excess liquid.</p>
<p>Combine mushroom stems, ricotta, sun-dried tomatoes, pine nuts and fresh herbs in a bowl and mix to combine. Season with a few pinches of salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>If using portobello mushrooms, sprinkle the underside of the mushrooms lightly with salt and pepper. Skip this step if using button mushrooms (I think it&#8217;s too fiddly and you&#8217;ve already seasoned the stuffing).</p>
<p>Place mushrooms on a baking tray, skin-side facing down, and fill with the ricotta stuffing. Your mushrooms are now ready to cook, but cooking time will depend on the size of your mushrooms and method of cooking. Small mushrooms will cook in 10 minutes under a grill, portobello mushrooms may take 30-40 mins to bake. As a guide, check button mushrooms after 10-15 minutes, and portobello mushrooms after 20-30 minutes. The mushrooms will be ready when the ricotta is golden-brown and the mushroom is heated through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banana egg flip</title>
		<link>/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 10:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It's something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/bananaeggflipeditedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It&#8217;s something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll make this in the morning, keep it in the fridge at work and find it&#8217;s still fine for evening consumption.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the LSA. For a dairy/lactose free option, replace the milk with soy milk or other non-dairy milk and likewise skip the yoghurt or use a non-dairy alternative.</p>
<p>Makes 1 large serving</p>
<ul>
<li>1 banana</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1/2 cup milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons natural or greek yoghurt</li>
<li>1 tablespoon LSA</li>
<li>2 teaspoons cocoa powder or 1/2 teaspoon vanilla essence (adjust to taste)</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. How easy is that?!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fried halloumi with caremalised fennel</title>
		<link>/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 14:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here's one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn't tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/caremalisedfennelhalloumi2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here&#8217;s one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn&#8217;t tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>
<p>Store bought halloumi will work just fine here, but if you&#8217;d like to have a go at making it yourself, the recipe I followed (which worked really well) can be found <a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/Halloumi.html" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;I ordered my cheese making supplies from <a href="http://www.greenlivingaustralia.com.au/" target="_blank">Green Living Australia</a> in Queensland who had fantastically speedy service. Making halloumi requires some patience, but the product is well worth it and it&#8217;s so satisfying to convert a big pot of milk into a tasty block of cheese oneself.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large bulb fennel, trimmed, quartered and cut into 5-10mm thick slices</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil, plus a little extra</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon caraway seeds, toasted and ground</li>
<li>pinch fennel seeds, toasted and ground (just add to the caraway and prepare together)</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried tarragon</li>
<li>1/4 cup white wine (optional)</li>
<li>1/4 cup loosely packed fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
<li>100g halloumi cheese, cut into 5mm thick slices</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat 2 tablespoons olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the fennel, ground spices and tarragon and cook until fennel begins to soften. Add the wine (if using, otherwise just keep cooking as is) and cook until pan is almost dry and fennel is tender and golden. If the pan dries out and fennel browns before cooking through, add a little water.</p>
<p>Transfer fennel to a bowl and toss with lemon juice and fresh herbs.</p>
<p>Rinse out the pan before cooking the halloumi. Unless using a non-stick pan, or if the teflon coating is starting to go, add a little oil to coat the pan. You don&#8217;t need much oil as the halloumi will release its own fat as it cooks. Turn the heat up to high and when the pan is nice and hot add the halloumi slices. Don&#8217;t add the halloumi while the pan is still cool or it will melt into a blob before a nice crust forms. Fry halloumi until light golden on the underside then flip and cook until both sides are light golden. This will only take around 1-2 minutes per side.</p>
<p>Arrange the fennel on plates and serve the fried halloumi atop the fennel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green smoothie</title>
		<link>/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 11:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​This smoothie really does taste better than anything its colour ought. It's sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Greensmoothie2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This smoothie really does taste much better than anything its colour ought. It&#8217;s sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>
<p>This recipe is based on one by <a href="http://theshiksa.com/2013/04/03/green-smoothie/" target="_blank">one by The Shiksa</a>. The slight graininess in the texture comes from the chia seeds; if you don&#8217;t like it cut down the chia or try soaking the seeds it in advance. If you want to soak the chia seeds, just pour a little hot water over them and stir, allow to sit for an hour or two then add the seeds and their soaking water to the smoothie.</p>
<p>When making this, don&#8217;t throw everything in the blender at once or you&#8217;ll end up with chunks in your smoothie. Add the fruit and kale one handful at a time and you&#8217;ll get much better results.</p>
<p>Makes around 1.4L which is enough for about 4 normal glasses, but I split this into two 750mL bottles and take one into work each day.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups cold water</li>
<li>1 pear, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1 granny smith apple, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup green grapes</li>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds</li>
<li>1 cup, loosely packed, fresh mint leaves</li>
<li>1/2 bunch (2-3 cups) kale, coarsely chopped</li>
<li>juice of 1 lime, about 2 tablespoons</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>8 or more ice cubes, depending on how cold you&#8217;d like it</li>
</ul>
<p>Place the water in a blender and add one handful of the pear/apple. Blend until smooth. Continue adding the pear and apple, a handful at a time, blending between each handful. Add the grapes and blend until smooth. Add the chia seeds, blend until smooth. Add the mint, blend again. Add the kale, again only a handful at a time, blending between each batch. Add the lime juice and cinnamon and blend until well mixed. Add the ice-cubes, blend until crushed and enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lemon scented silverbeet with currants</title>
		<link>/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 12:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.​</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/silverbeetlemoncurrants2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.</p>
<p>Serves 2-3 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 bunch silverbeet, rinsed, stems removed and coarsely chopped</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>2 tablespoons currants</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add silverbeet and lemon juice and toss to coat silverbeet with the lemon and oil. I like to add the currants now too, as cooking them with the silverbeet will make them nice and juicy. Cook, stirring frequently, until silverbeet is just wilted, about 5 minutes. Serve immediately.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Broccoli salad</title>
		<link>/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn't like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/broccolisaladeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn&#8217;t like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>
<p>Despite the broccoli, this is actually quite a sweet salad, so keep this in mind when thinking about what to pair it with (perhaps a quiche or grilled fish).</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, just skip the almonds.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 heads broccoli, stems and florets, chopped into bite-size pieces</li>
<li>1/2 cup mayonnaise*</li>
<li>1 scant tablespoon red wine vinegar</li>
<li>2 teaspoons honey</li>
<li>1/4 red onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup dried cranberries</li>
<li>1/2 cup flaked or slivered almonds, toasted</li>
</ul>
<p>*On this occasion I used homemade mayonnaise, which was delicious, but I have made this with store-bought before and that works too. This was my first time making mayonnaise so I haven&#8217;t developed my own version yet, but if you&#8217;re interested, the recipe I followed can be found <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/wordofmouth/2010/jul/01/how-to-make-perfect-mayonnaise" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Steam the broccoli until just tender, you want it to retain some crispness so try and avoid over-cooking. The stems will take a little longer to cook, so I generally start steaming these first, then after a few minutes add the florets and steam for another couple of minutes. When cooked, swirl the broccoli in icy water to chill. This will both stop the cooking and chill it for the salad. Drain and pat dry.</p>
<p>To make the dressing, mix mayonnaise, vinegar and honey together in a small bowl.</p>
<p>Combine broccoli, onion and cranberries. Pour in dressing and toss to coat. Sprinkle the almonds over the top just before serving. (The cranberries and onion have a habit of accumulating in the bottom of a large salad bowl, so take note to scoop these up as you&#8217;re serving the broccoli.)</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
