<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Breakfast &amp; brunch &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/breakfast-brunch/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 05:40:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Buckwheat porridge</title>
		<link>/2013/06/23/2013-6-23-buckwheat-porridge/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 10:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/23/2013-6-23-buckwheat-porridge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Winter has well and truly settled upon Canberra, and winter means cold mornings and warm breakfasts. The medical advice in Australia is that oats are not safe for those with coeliac disease. (I know this varies in other countries.) When I was first diagnosed my gastroenterologist explained that the reason for this is two-fold: First, oats and wheat are usually grown in adjacent&#160;fields&#160;and processed on the same equipment so the risk of cross-contamination is very high. Second, oats contain a protein (called avenin) which is similar in structure to gluten and which around 1 in 5 coeliacs also react to.&#160;<a href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/coeliac-disease/faq.html">Coeliac Australia</a>&#160;explain that there is no way to test who will react to avenin in advance, and so they actually class avenin as a type of gluten and advise that coeliacs shout not eat oats. I developed this recipe the first winter after I was diagnosed with coeliac disease and it has been our regular cold-weather breakfast ever since.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/buckwheatporridgeeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Winter has well and truly settled upon Canberra, and winter means cold mornings and warm breakfasts. The medical advice in Australia is that oats are not safe for those with coeliac disease. (I know this varies in other countries.) When I was first diagnosed my gastroenterologist explained that the reason for this is two-fold: First, oats and wheat are often grown in adjacent&nbsp;fields&nbsp;and processed on the same equipment so the risk of cross-contamination is very high. Second, oats contain a protein (called avenin) which is similar in structure to gluten and which around 1 in 5 coeliacs also react to. <a href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/coeliac-disease/faq.html" target="_blank">Coeliac Australia</a> explain that there is no way to test who will react to avenin in advance, and so they actually class avenin as a type of gluten and advise that coeliacs should not eat oats. I developed this recipe the first winter after I was diagnosed with coeliac disease and it has been our regular cold-weather breakfast ever since.</p>
<p>I make up containers of the mixed fruit and toasted nuts in advance and keep these in the pantry (store the fruit and nuts separately though to help keep the nuts nice and crunchy). The porridge can be left to simmer while you go and have a shower, but I&#8217;d only recommend this if you&#8217;ve made it a few times and know your stove so it neither boils over nor burns on the bottom in the mean time.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version skip the nuts. I started using soy milk as my partner is lactose-intolerant, but if lactose is okay you could substitute dairy milk.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1/3 cup buckwheat</li>
<li>1 cup soy milk, plus extra to serve</li>
<li>1 cardamon pod, bruised</li>
<li>2 cloves</li>
<li>1-inch piece cinnamon stick (a rolling pin works well to break up a tough stick of cinnamon)&nbsp;</li>
<li>1 apple or pear, cored and cut into 1-2cm cubes</li>
<li>1 banana, thinly sliced</li>
<li>2 tablespoons mixed dried fruit (I use sultanas, cranberries, and chopped dried apricots)&nbsp;</li>
<li>2 tablespoons mixed nuts, toasted (I use slivered almonds, chopped hazelnuts and chopped walnuts)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey, or to taste (I just dip the tip of each dessert spoon in the honey as serving and this is about right)&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine buckwheat, 1 cup milk and the spices in a small saucepan over a medium heat and bring to the boil. Reduce heat to low and simmer, stirring&nbsp;occasionally,&nbsp;until buckwheat is tender and milk absorbed, 20-30 minutes depending on how strong a simmer you have. If porridge dries out, add a little extra milk or the liquid from stewing the fruit (keep reading).</p>
<p>Meanwhile, stew the apple or pear: Place apple or pear in a small microwave-safe bowl, and pour over enough water to barely cover the fruit. Microwave for 3-5 minutes until tender then drain. (A ripe pear will cook in 3 minutes, an apple covered with cold water will need 5 minutes.)</p>
<p>Once the buckwheat is cooked, fish out the spices. Mix in banana and apple or pear and divide into two cereal bowls. Sprinkle each bowl with a spoonful each of dried fruit and nuts, stir through a little honey and add extra milk to taste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pumpkin quinoa porridge</title>
		<link>/2013/04/22/2013-4-22-pumpkin-quinoa-porridge/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 14:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/22/2013-4-22-pumpkin-quinoa-porridge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Being a porridge, this is a lovely warm and sweet breakfast or brunch dish, but I did have it for dinner the other night when I was feeling in need of something cosy. I'd had a nap in the afternoon and woke up feeling more groggy than refreshed and thinking that if I was going to cook dinner it had better be particularly comforting and not too involved. So, I made this pumpkin quinoa porridge, and it has rapidly become a regular at my table.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pumpkinquinoaporridge.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Being a porridge, this is a lovely warm and sweet breakfast or brunch dish, but I did have it for dinner the other night when I was feeling in need of something cosy. I&#8217;d had a nap in the afternoon and woke up feeling more groggy than refreshed and thinking that if I was going to cook dinner it had better be particularly comforting and not too involved. So, I made this pumpkin quinoa porridge, and it has rapidly become a regular at my table.</p>
</p>
<p>The recipe is based on one from the&nbsp;<a href="http://withfoodandlove.com/breakfast-brunch/first-of-fall/" target="_blank">With Food + Love</a>&nbsp;blog by Sherrie Castellano.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The pumpkin puree and quinoa can be cooked in larger batches in advance and kept in the fridge for a few days, making it super quick and easy to throw this together for breakfast on a chilly morning.</p>
<p>For a dairy/lactose-free version, use soy or other non-dairy milk. For a vegan alternative, use a non-dairy milk and replace the honey with agave nectar or maple syrup.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1/3 cup quinoa (makes about 1 cup when cooked)</li>
<li>1cm piece cinnamon stick</li>
<li>1 cardamon pod</li>
<li>2 cloves</li>
<li>1 pear or granny smith apple, cored and cut into 1-2cm cubes</li>
<li>2/3 cup <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/22/pumpkin-quinoa-porridge#pumpkinpuree">pumpkin puree (recipe below)</a></li>
<li>1/2 cup milk</li>
<li>1/3 cup sultanas</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon vanilla extract (or seeds scraped from 1/4 vanilla pod)</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>a few pinches ground nutmeg</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine quinoa, cinnamon stick, cardamon and cloves with 2/3 cup boiling water in a saucepan over medium-low heat. Simmer until quinoa is tender and water absorbed, 15-20 minutes. Add a little extra water if needed while cooking. Once quinoa is cooked, remove from stove and fish out the spices.</p>
<p>Place pear or apple in a small microwave safe bowl, and add enough boiling water to barely cover the fruit. Microwave for 3-5 minutes until tender, then drain. A ripe pear will be done in 3 minutes, while a firmer pear or an apple will need 4-5 minutes.</p>
<p>Add pear or apple, pumpkin puree, milk, sultanas, vanilla, ground spices and honey to the quinoa. Add a little extra milk if needed. Return to the stove and cook over medium heat, stirring&nbsp;occasionally, until hot. Adjust spices and honey to taste and serve immediately.</p>
<p><a name="pumpkinpuree"></a></p>
<h3>Pumpkin puree</h3>
<p>Quantity will depend very much on the size of your pumpkin. Many recipes will only call for a small fraction-of-a-pumpkin-worth of puree, but I usually cook half or the whole pumpkin and keep the extra on hand in the fridge. I&#8217;ve suggested two methods for cooking the pumpkin below: boiling/steaming requires more &#8216;hands-on&#8217; time, but will cook the pumpkin more quickly; roasting the pumpkin will take an hour or two, but it only needs about 5 minutes of your time, so you can do something else while the pumpkin&#8217;s cooking. Personally I prefer roasting, it just means being a bit organised.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 butternut pumpkin</li>
<li>olive oil (if roasting)</li>
</ul>
<p>Cook the pumpkin:</p>
<p>To boil/steam: Peel and seed pumpkin and cut into 2cm cubes. Boil or steam until pumpkin is very tender, then drain.</p>
<p>To roast: Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F). Cut pumpkin in half lengthwise and scoop out the seeds. Brush cut sides lightly with olive oil. Place, cut sides down, on a baking tray and roast until pumpkin is very soft. This will take about 1.5 hours although cooking time will vary depending on the size of your pumpkin. You can test if the pumpkin is cooked through using a skewer. Peel the skin away from the pumpkin (or if it&#8217;s not coming away easily, turn pumpkin halves over and scoop out the flesh).</p>
<p>Puree the pumpkin flesh either with a potato masher/fork or in a food processor. In the case of the latter, it&#8217;s generally a good idea to allow the pumpkin to cool slightly before processing. Using a food processor will give you a smooth puree, while mashing by hand will result in a &#8216;chunkier&#8217; consistency.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banana, almond and coconut pancakes</title>
		<link>/2013/03/30/2013-3-30-banana-almond-and-coconut-pancakes/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 04:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/03/30/2013-3-30-banana-almond-and-coconut-pancakes/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I'm not often one for luxurious brunches, partly because I usually wake up starving and want to eat breakfast straight away, and partly because of my weekend morning routine: Saturday mornings it's off to the Farmers' Market, and I do a Sunday morning gym class. Over Easter, however, the Farmers' Market aren't on and my gym's not running its usual classes, which has made way for lazy mornings over these somewhat indulgent pancakes.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Bananaalmondcoconutpancakeseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I&#8217;m not often one for luxurious brunches, partly because I usually wake up starving and want to eat breakfast straight away, and partly because of my weekend morning routine: Saturday mornings it&#8217;s off to the Farmers&#8217; Market, and I do a Sunday morning gym class. Over Easter, however, the Farmers&#8217; Market aren&#8217;t on and my gym&#8217;s not running its usual classes, which has made way for lazy mornings over these somewhat indulgent pancakes.</p>
<p>These pancakes are a good way to use up bananas which have ripened beyond eating fresh.&nbsp;They are thicker than your usual pancakes, more fritter- or muffin-like, which works especially well with the crunchiness of the toasted almonds. The almonds could be toasted, the dry ingredients mixed and toppings prepared the night before to make these really quick in the morning.</p>
<p>      <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/bananaalmondcoconutpancakes2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Serves 3 generously, or perhaps 4 more respectably! (Makes about 9 8cm-diameter pancakes.)</p>
<ul>
<li>1/2 cup almond meal</li>
<li>1/4 cup coconut flour</li>
<li>1/2 cup plain gluten-free flour*</li>
<li>3 teaspoons baking powder</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>1 cup ripe bananas, mashed (2 large or 3 small bananas)</li>
<li>2 eggs, lightly whisked</li>
<li>1/2 cup coconut milk</li>
<li>1 tablespoon amaretti (alternatively you could try substituting 1 &#8211; 2 teaspoons almond essence)</li>
<li>1/4 cup slivered almonds, toasted</li>
<li>1 teaspoon butter</li>
<li>Maple syrup or honey, seasonal fruit or other toppings to serve**</li>
</ul>
<p>*I use the brown rice gluten-free flour mix suggested in&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gluten-Free-Baking-Classics-Annalise-Roberts/dp/1572840994%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1572840994">Gluten-Free Baking Classics</a></em>, by Annalise Roberts: 6 parts brown rice flour : 2 parts potato starch : 1 part tapioca starch.</p>
<p>**The pancakes I served up were topped with maple syrup and apple sauce with fresh strawberries in one case, and cinnamon baked pear with strawberry sauce in the other. Recipes for the <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/banana-almond-and-coconut-pancakes#applesauce">apple sauce</a>, <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/banana-almond-and-coconut-pancakes#strawberrysauce">strawberry sauce</a> and <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/banana-almond-and-coconut-pancakes#cinnamonbakedpear">cinnamon baked pear</a> are below.</p>
<p>Optional: preheat oven to a very low heat (60-80˚C or 140-180F); you can use this to keep the first batches of pancakes warm while cooking the rest.</p>
<p>Combine all dry ingredients, except slivered almonds, in a large mixing bowl and mix well. In a separate, smaller bowl, combine wet ingredients except the butter.</p>
<p>Add the wet ingredients to the dry and stir until well combined. Stir in the toasted almonds. The batter will be much thicker and stickier than your usual pancake batter, more like a cake mix.</p>
<p>Heat a non-stick frying pan over a medium-low heat and melt a third of the butter in the pan. Add spoonfuls of the batter (roughly 1/3 cup in size) and use the back of a metal spoon to spread out until 1cm thick. Pancakes will be about 8-10cm in diameter. Cook until underside is golden, about 10 minutes. Flip and cook until golden on both sides. Place pancakes on an oven-proof plate or tray, lined with paper towels, and keep warm in the oven while you repeat to cook the remaining batter.</p>
<p>Serve&nbsp;immediately, topped with maple syrup or honey and fresh and/or cooked fruit.</p>
<p><a name="applesauce"></a></p>
<h3>Apple Sauce</h3>
<p>Makes roughly &nbsp;1 1/2 cups, which is about right for the above quantity of pancakes.</p>
<ul>
<li>3 granny-smith* apples, peeled, cored and chopped into about 1cm pieces</li>
<li>1/2-1 teaspoon ground cinnamon, or 1/2 a cinnamon stick</li>
<li>1/4-1/2 teaspoon ground cloves, or 9 whole cloves</li>
<li>1 teaspoon raw sugar (white would also work)</li>
</ul>
<p>*if you happen to have a different variety of apples on hand, go ahead and use them, but omit the sugar. You could also use a similar recipe with pears.</p>
<p>Place apples in a small saucepan and add barely enough boiling water to cover. If using cinnamon stick and whole cloves add these now as well. Simmer until apple is soft and mushy, about 5-10 minutes.</p>
<p>Drain apples, and fish out the spices (if added). Mash the apple. Add sugar and ground spices (if using) to taste and you&#8217;re done. This sauce will keep in the fridge for a few days.</p>
<p><a name="strawberrysauce"></a></p>
<h3>Strawberry Sauce</h3>
<p>Makes roughly &nbsp;1 1/2 cups, which is generous for the above quantity of pancakes as this sauce is very strong.</p>
<ul>
<li>500g fresh strawberries*, stems removed, halved</li>
<li>Juice of half a lemon (about 1 &#8211; 1 1/2 tablespoons. You could also try substituting balsamic vinegar, in which case you might want to cut down the sugar)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon caster sugar</li>
<li>1 teaspoon vanilla essence</li>
</ul>
<p>*This recipe will work with most fresh or frozen berries, just adjust the sugar and lemon juice to taste.</p>
<p>Place strawberries in a small saucepan over a medium heat, and toss with sugar and lemon juice. Cook, stirring occasionally, until strawberries are soft, about 10-15 minutes. Break the strawberries up a bit if they are large or haven&#8217;t started to disintegrate. Mix in vanilla essence.</p>
<p>Allow to cool slightly before serving. This sauce will keep in the fridge for a few days.</p>
<p><a name="cinnamonbakedpear"></a></p>
<h3>Cinnamon Baked Pear</h3>
<p>Serves 3-4 as a pancake topping, again matching the above quantity of pancakes.</p>
<ul>
<li>2 pears*, cored and cut into thin wedges/slices (about 5mm at their thickest point)</li>
<li>A few pinches cinnamon</li>
<li>Olive oil</li>
</ul>
<p>*This would also work well with apples or perhaps peaches, but for peaches I&#8217;d double the thickness of the slices.</p>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F). Brush a baking tray lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Spread pear slices in a single layer on the baking tray, and sprinkle with cinnamon. Bake until pear is tender, about 15-20 minutes. Very ripe fruit might cook more quickly, slightly under-ripe will take a bit longer.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breakfast smoothie</title>
		<link>/2013/03/11/2013-3-11-breakfast-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 03:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/03/11/2013-3-11-breakfast-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am very much a creature of habit when it comes to breakfast. Breakfast for me takes one of two forms, almost every day of the year. These smoothies are my warm-weather breakfast. (You'll find out what my cold-weather breakfast is when the Canberra weather decides to turn chilly for the year). Don't let the apparent monotony fool you, breakfast is one of my favourite meals of the day as it's so very yummy!</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/smoothieresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I am very much a creature of habit when it comes to breakfast. Breakfast for me takes one of two forms, almost every day of the year. These smoothies are my warm-weather breakfast. (You&#8217;ll find out what my cold-weather breakfast is when the Canberra weather decides to turn chilly for the year). Don&#8217;t let the apparent monotony fool you, breakfast is one of my favourite meals of the day as it&#8217;s so very yummy!</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>2 bananas, cut into thick slices (unless you&#8217;re using a mango, in which case only use 1 banana)</li>
<li>125-150g silken tofu</li>
<li>4 heaped tablespoons, about 1/2 cup, natural yoghurt</li>
<li>1/2 cup apple juice</li>
</ul>
<p>and one of:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups frozen rasberries, strawberries or mixed berries; or</li>
<li>1 cup frozen blueberries (substitute dairy or soy milk for the apple juice, I find the blueberries and apple juice a bit too sweet); or</li>
<li>flesh of 1 mango (only use one banana, you may like to try orange or tropical juice instead of apple, also it wont be as chilly as using frozen berries, so add a few&nbsp;ice-blocks&nbsp;as well); or</li>
<li>try your own fruit combinations, or just leave it as a plain banana smoothie.</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. Pour into glasses and enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
