<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Drinks &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/drinks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 05:40:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Snickers bar smoothie</title>
		<link>/2014/12/09/2014-12-9-snickers-bar-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 06:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet treats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/12/09/2014-12-9-snickers-bar-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>Deliciousness in a glass! I mean seriously, who needs junk food when you can make treats like this that are made with proper&#160;food and contain real nutrients while also making your taste buds super happy?!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/img-2.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Deliciousness in a glass! I mean seriously, who needs junk food when you can make treats like this that are made with proper&nbsp;food and contain real nutrients while also making your taste buds super happy?!</p>
<p>For vegan and dairy/lactose free alternatives, use soy or other non-dairy&nbsp;milk and either skip the yoghurt or try replacing it with silken tofu or non-dairy yoghurt.</p>
<p>Serves 1</p>
<ul>
<li>1 banana, peeled and cut into chunks</li>
<li>¼ cup skim milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons peanut butter</li>
<li>2 tablespoons natural yoghurt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon cocoa powder</li>
<li>½ cup ice blocks (adjust depending on how cold you&#8217;d like your smoothie, alternatively use frozen banana and skip the ice).</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citrus chia &#8216;frogs eggs&#8217;</title>
		<link>/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 23:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p><p><span style="font-size:15px">This snack idea is so simple I almost didn't post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I've had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.</span><span style="font-size:15px">&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Chiagoupeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p><span>&nbsp;</span>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p>
<p>This snack idea is so simple I almost didn&#8217;t post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I&#8217;ve had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>I particularly like chia prepared this way because it&#8217;s an energy source that&#8217;s light enough that I can drink it then proceed to exercise 15 minutes later without feeling remotely ill &#8211; even if that exercise is teaching Body Attack with it&#8217;s tuck-jump-burpees. There are not many foods for which I can say the same.</p>
<p>Now for the credits: idea courtesy of my sister, and the name&#8230; inspired by my mother who came close to convincing her squad of swimmers,&nbsp;using post-exercise nutritional arguments,&nbsp;that she was in fact drinking frogs eggs!</p>
<p>Serves 1</p>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds (any colour)</li>
<li>juice of half a lemon or lime (if you like stronger citrus flavours, add juice from the whole fruit)</li>
<li>300mL water</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar. Secure lid and shake well. Shake a couple of times over the next 5-10 minutes so the chia doesn&#8217;t clump together too densely. Refrigerate or allow to sit for at least 30 minutes and you&#8217;re done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banana egg flip</title>
		<link>/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 10:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It's something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/bananaeggflipeditedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It&#8217;s something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll make this in the morning, keep it in the fridge at work and find it&#8217;s still fine for evening consumption.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the LSA. For a dairy/lactose free option, replace the milk with soy milk or other non-dairy milk and likewise skip the yoghurt or use a non-dairy alternative.</p>
<p>Makes 1 large serving</p>
<ul>
<li>1 banana</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1/2 cup milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons natural or greek yoghurt</li>
<li>1 tablespoon LSA</li>
<li>2 teaspoons cocoa powder or 1/2 teaspoon vanilla essence (adjust to taste)</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. How easy is that?!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green smoothie</title>
		<link>/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 11:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​This smoothie really does taste better than anything its colour ought. It's sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Greensmoothie2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This smoothie really does taste much better than anything its colour ought. It&#8217;s sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>
<p>This recipe is based on one by <a href="http://theshiksa.com/2013/04/03/green-smoothie/" target="_blank">one by The Shiksa</a>. The slight graininess in the texture comes from the chia seeds; if you don&#8217;t like it cut down the chia or try soaking the seeds it in advance. If you want to soak the chia seeds, just pour a little hot water over them and stir, allow to sit for an hour or two then add the seeds and their soaking water to the smoothie.</p>
<p>When making this, don&#8217;t throw everything in the blender at once or you&#8217;ll end up with chunks in your smoothie. Add the fruit and kale one handful at a time and you&#8217;ll get much better results.</p>
<p>Makes around 1.4L which is enough for about 4 normal glasses, but I split this into two 750mL bottles and take one into work each day.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups cold water</li>
<li>1 pear, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1 granny smith apple, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup green grapes</li>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds</li>
<li>1 cup, loosely packed, fresh mint leaves</li>
<li>1/2 bunch (2-3 cups) kale, coarsely chopped</li>
<li>juice of 1 lime, about 2 tablespoons</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>8 or more ice cubes, depending on how cold you&#8217;d like it</li>
</ul>
<p>Place the water in a blender and add one handful of the pear/apple. Blend until smooth. Continue adding the pear and apple, a handful at a time, blending between each handful. Add the grapes and blend until smooth. Add the chia seeds, blend until smooth. Add the mint, blend again. Add the kale, again only a handful at a time, blending between each batch. Add the lime juice and cinnamon and blend until well mixed. Add the ice-cubes, blend until crushed and enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breakfast smoothie</title>
		<link>/2013/03/11/2013-3-11-breakfast-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 03:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/03/11/2013-3-11-breakfast-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I am very much a creature of habit when it comes to breakfast. Breakfast for me takes one of two forms, almost every day of the year. These smoothies are my warm-weather breakfast. (You'll find out what my cold-weather breakfast is when the Canberra weather decides to turn chilly for the year). Don't let the apparent monotony fool you, breakfast is one of my favourite meals of the day as it's so very yummy!</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/smoothieresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I am very much a creature of habit when it comes to breakfast. Breakfast for me takes one of two forms, almost every day of the year. These smoothies are my warm-weather breakfast. (You&#8217;ll find out what my cold-weather breakfast is when the Canberra weather decides to turn chilly for the year). Don&#8217;t let the apparent monotony fool you, breakfast is one of my favourite meals of the day as it&#8217;s so very yummy!</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>2 bananas, cut into thick slices (unless you&#8217;re using a mango, in which case only use 1 banana)</li>
<li>125-150g silken tofu</li>
<li>4 heaped tablespoons, about 1/2 cup, natural yoghurt</li>
<li>1/2 cup apple juice</li>
</ul>
<p>and one of:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups frozen rasberries, strawberries or mixed berries; or</li>
<li>1 cup frozen blueberries (substitute dairy or soy milk for the apple juice, I find the blueberries and apple juice a bit too sweet); or</li>
<li>flesh of 1 mango (only use one banana, you may like to try orange or tropical juice instead of apple, also it wont be as chilly as using frozen berries, so add a few&nbsp;ice-blocks&nbsp;as well); or</li>
<li>try your own fruit combinations, or just leave it as a plain banana smoothie.</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. Pour into glasses and enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
