<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nut-free friendly &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/nut-free-friendly/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 05:40:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tegan Salad</title>
		<link>/2015/02/23/2015-1-1-tegan-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/23/2015-1-1-tegan-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">I tend to get a little concerned when I hear the 'vegetarian'&#160;conversation&#160;going on in the background while I'm cooking. It goes something like this:&#160;my partner being quizzed by our dinner guest along the lines of "so are you vegetarian too?", "do you always eat vegetarian meals?", "do you mind not eating meat at home?", "what about protein?",&#160;etc., etc. Fast forward an hour or two and said guest has not only complemented the meal but&#160;scraped his plate clean and even volunteered to do the washing up (actions speak louder than words)...&#160;I think maybe I've changed someone's mind on vegetarian cooking!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/img.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>I tend to get a little concerned when I hear the &#8216;vegetarian&#8217; conversation going on in the background while I&#8217;m cooking. It goes something like this: my partner being quizzed by our dinner guest along the lines of &#8220;so are you vegetarian too?&#8221;, &#8220;do you always eat vegetarian meals?&#8221;, &#8220;do you mind not eating meat at home?&#8221;, &#8220;what about protein?&#8221;, etc., etc. Fast forward an hour or two and said guest has not only complemented the meal but scraped his plate clean and even volunteered to do the washing up (actions speak louder than words)&#8230; I think maybe I&#8217;ve changed someone&#8217;s mind on vegetarian cooking!</p>
<p>This recipe came about by combining a mango and halloumi salad suggestion from my good friend Tegan, with a mango and avocado salad recipe from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Joy-Cooking-All-About-Vegetarian/dp/B0002Y0SII%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3DB0002Y0SII" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joy of Cooking: All About Vegetarian Cooking</a> by Irma Rombauer et al., along with some tweaks of my own. If you&#8217;ve tried my recipes before, hopefully you&#8217;ve learned that even (or especially) when you read an ingredients list and the words &#8220;unlikely combination&#8221; come to mind, the result is going to be good. If you&#8217;re new to my blog then trust me, this is worth being a little adventurous!</p>
<p>I often include eggs with the salad to turn in into a complete meal, but I also like serving it without the eggs alongside panfried fish or to add a bit of &#8216;wow&#8217; factor to a spread. The number of eggs is also easily varied according to appetite: after something slightly lighter? make it 1 egg per person, feeding a hungry man after a big training session? pile on some extra eggs and maybe add a side with more carbs.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the macadamias. For a vegan and dairy/lactose free salad, leave out the eggs and halloumi and the resulting mango and avocado salad is still a great combination!</p>
<p>Serves 4</p>
<ul>
<li>½ cup macadamia nuts</li>
<li>1 lemon, juiced (around 3 tablespoons lemon juice)</li>
<li>2 avocados</li>
<li>2 small-medium mangoes or 1 large</li>
<li>½ red onion</li>
<li>2 or 3 tablespoons olive oil (use 3 tablespoons if you&#8217;re including eggs, otherwise just use 2)</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>¼ cup fresh basil, finely chopped</li>
<li>4 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>8 eggs (optional)</li>
<li>200g halloumi</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 160˚C (320 F). Coarsely chop the macadamias then spread on a baking tray. Bake in oven until macadamias are fragrant and lightly toasted. If your oven is preheated this will only take 3-5 minutes, although they may need longer if the oven&#8217;s still heating up. Keep a close eye on them, nuts will generally go from raw to burnt very easily if you get distracted. Once the macadamias are toasted set them aside until you&#8217;re ready to serve.</p>
<p>Place half the lemon juice in a medium-sized bowl. Slice the avocados lengthwise and remove the stones. Score flesh into approximately 1cm pieces then scoop it away from the skin and place in the bowl of lemon juice. Toss to coat the avocado with lemon juice &#8211; this will help prevent browning (which is quite harmless but aesthetically not very pleasing).</p>
<p>Cut the mango(es) into approximately 1 cm pieces and add to the avocado. Peel and finely slice the red onion; add it to the mango and avocado then toss to combine.</p>
<p>Make the dressing: combine 2 tablespoon olive oil, the remaining lemon juice, finely chopped basil and a pinch each of salt and pepper in a jar and shake to combine.</p>
<p>Divide baby spinach between serving plates and spoon avocado and mango mixture over the top.</p>
<p>If serving with eggs: depending on your frying pan you may need to cook the eggs in a few batches. Heat the remaining tablespoon (or for batches, portion there-of) of olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Keeping the medium heat, fry the eggs for a 2-3 minutes on each side until light golden and cooked through. Serve alongside the salad and season with a little salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>Finally, cook the halloumi. This is very quick so I do it last after I&#8217;ve cooked the eggs. Use the frying pan from the eggs that&#8217;s still hot, or heat your frying pan over a hot stove then turn the heat down to medium. Placing halloumi into an already hot pan will ensure it forms a delicious golden crust while melting on the inside (whereas if it cooks too slowly you may end up with a blob of molten cheese in your pan). There&#8217;s generally enough fat in the halloumi that it doesn&#8217;t need extra oil for cooking, especially if you&#8217;re using a non-stick frying pan. Cook over a medium heat for about 1 minute on each side until halloumi is golden brown then server over the salad.</p>
<p>Give the dressing you made another shake to ensure it&#8217;s well mixed then drizzle over the salad. Sprinkle with macadamia nuts and you&#8217;re good to go. Happy Dinner! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Egg &#038; quinoa salad with Moroccan spices &#038; lime-infused yoghurt</title>
		<link>/2015/01/20/2014-12-24-egg-quinoa-salad-with-moroccan-spices-lime-infused-yoghurt/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 03:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/20/2014-12-24-egg-quinoa-salad-with-moroccan-spices-lime-infused-yoghurt/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>If visiting family interstate for a couple of weeks taught me something it's this: eating out of someone else's kitchen is the mother of culinary invention. If you're travelling, house-sitting, or for whatever reason&#160;don't have access to your favourite go-to ingredients, rather than getting frustrated or feeling defeated&#160;why not view it as an opportunity to get creative?&#160;It's moments like these when some of my favourite meals come into being;&#160;I may not even know quite what I'm making until I'm almost done, I just start putting things together and see where the food leads me. In this case it was to a refreshing, satisfying and nutritious lunch. Can't have too many yummy&#160;salad ideas methinks.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img-1.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>If visiting family interstate for a couple of weeks taught me something it&#8217;s this: eating out of someone else&#8217;s kitchen is the mother of culinary invention. If you&#8217;re travelling, house-sitting, or for whatever reason don&#8217;t have access to your favourite go-to ingredients, rather than getting frustrated or feeling defeated why not view it as an opportunity to get creative? It&#8217;s moments like these when some of my favourite meals come into being; I may not even know quite what I&#8217;m making until I&#8217;m almost done, I just start putting things together and see where the food leads me. In this case it was to a refreshing, satisfying and nutritious lunch. Can&#8217;t have too many yummy salad ideas methinks.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the almonds and seeds if needs be.</p>
<p>Serves 4</p>
<ul>
<li>4 eggs</li>
<li>Spices as follow:
<ul>
<li>1 teaspoon ras el hanout</li>
<li>½ teaspoon ground cumin</li>
<li>½ teaspoon ground coriander seeds</li>
<li>¼ teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>⅔ cup quinoa</li>
<li>2 teaspoons canola oil</li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14px;">2 teaspoons olive oil</span></li>
<li><span style="font-size: 14px;">salt and pepper (optional, to taste)</span></li>
<li><a href="#limeyoghurt"><span style="font-size: 14px;">¾ cup </span>lime-infused yoghurt (recipe below)</a></li>
<li>250g cherry tomatoes, halved</li>
<li>4 cups leafy greens (I used baby spinach and baby kale but other greens, based on your preferences and availability, should also work; for larger leaves remove any tough or fibrous stems and cut or tear the leaves into bite sized pieces)</li>
<li>½ cup almonds, coarsely chopped and lightly toasted</li>
<li>2 teaspoon chia seeds</li>
<li>2 teaspoons linseeds</li>
</ul>
<p>Hard boil the eggs: Place eggs in a saucepan and add enough cold water to completely cover them. Bring water to a boil over a high heat then reduce heat to medium and simmer for 12 minutes. Remove eggs and set aside to cool.</p>
<p>Meanwhile combine the spices in the bottom of a saucepan and heat gently until fragrant. Set aside about 1<span style="font-size: 14px;"> teaspoon of the spices but leave the rest in the saucepan.</span> Add the quinoa and canola oil to the saucepan with the spices and stir to combine. Cook over a medium heat, stirring frequently, for 2-3 minutes. Remove the saucepan from the heat for 5 minutes (this will allow it to cool a bit so it doesn&#8217;t hiss too much and spit your quinoa out of the when you add water). Add 1¼ cups water to the saucepan, stir to mix with the quinoa, and return to the stove. Simmer over a low heat until water is absorbed and quinoa just cooked, adding a little extra water if needed. The quinoa will be cooked when the little rings start to separate from the central seed.</p>
<p>Once the eggs are cool enough to handle you can peel them (this can also be done under running cold water while the eggs are still hot): tap all sides against a hard surface, like your kitchen bench, to crack the shell then peel it away; getting under the thin &#8216;skin&#8217; between the egg and shell will make it easier to peel the shell away.</p>
<p>Cut the eggs into about 1 cm (<span style="font-size: 14px;">½ inch) chunks. In a small bowl, toss the eggs with the</span><span style="font-size: 14px;"> teaspoon of spices you set aside earlier, the olive oil and a pinch each of salt and pepper, if using. Add eggs to the quinoa along with the tomatoes and toss to combine.</span></p>
<p>To serve, divide leafy greens between bowls then top with quinoa salad. Spoon the lime-infused yoghurt over the top and sprinkle with the almonds, chia seeds and linseeds. Toss or mix it all together to eat!</p>
<h2 id="limeyoghurt">Lime-infused yoghurt</h2>
<p>Makes about ¾ cup</p>
<ul>
<li>1 lime</li>
<li>⅓ cup fresh mint leaves</li>
<li>⅔ cup natural yoghurt</li>
<li>freshly ground black pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Use the finest side of your grater or a microplane to zest the lime; then juice the lime. Finely chop the mint. Combine mint, lime zest and juice and yoghurt in a small bowl and mix to combine. Season with a pinch or two of pepper, to taste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crunchy mixed greens with mustard vinaigrette</title>
		<link>/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 01:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px"><em>"There might not be enough food... the boys are coming and&#160;they eat A LOT"</em> -&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">Lil' Sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch. Despite being fairly confident that&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">there would be plenty of food</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;I agreed to add an extra dish,</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;opting</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&#160;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&#160;(Admittedly&#160;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&#160;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&#160;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img-5.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<figure>
<blockquote><p>
    <span>&#8220;</span>There might not be enough food&#8230; the boys are coming and they eat A LOT.<span>&#8221;</span><br />
  </blockquote><figcaption class="source">&mdash; Lil&#8217; sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite being fairly confident that&nbsp;there would be plenty of food&nbsp;I agreed to add an extra dish,&nbsp;opting&nbsp;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&nbsp;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&nbsp;(Admittedly&nbsp;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&nbsp;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&nbsp;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</p>
<p>Back home and through the process of testing the recipe this salad&nbsp;has rapidly become a favourite. Only thing is, there are two versions and I can&#8217;t decide which I like best, so I&#8217;ve included both options and you can choose for yourself.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The question before you is this: pomegranate or cranberries? The pomegranate seeds are refreshing and add a nice crunch. The cranberries are sweeter and slightly chewy. I like both versions. I&#8217;d suggest the pomegranate&nbsp;as a nice refreshing choice&nbsp;on a&nbsp;warm day, and the cranberries when you&#8217;re looking to bring a little more sweetness to the meal. Dried cranberries are also typically easier to come by than fresh pomegranates.</p>
<p><span style="font-size:14px">I haven&#8217;t included rocket in my leafy greens.&nbsp;Personally I don&#8217;t like rocket&nbsp;&#8211;&nbsp;I find it too hot &#8211;&nbsp;while the watercress here is just a little peppery.&nbsp;If you are a fan of rocket&nbsp;I suspect if would work well in this salad, and I always encourage experimentation when cooking.</span></p>
<p>For a nut free version, skip the almonds. It won&#8217;t be as crunchy but the combination of flavours should still survive. For a vegan or dairy/lactose-free alternative, omit the parmesan.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 cups baby kale</li>
<li>2 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>1 cup watercress leaves, removed from stems</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> cup almonds</li>
<li>1 pomegranate or ½ cup dried cranberries</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> cup shaved parmesan</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> red onion, finely sliced or diced</li>
<li><a href="#"><span style="font-size:14px">⅓ cup m</span>ustard Vinaigrette (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If using a&nbsp;pomegranate, start by seeding the fruit (otherwise, skip straight to the next paragraph). Tori&nbsp;Avey provides some great instructions explaining&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://toriavey.com/toris-kitchen/2011/09/how-to-seed-a-pomegranate/#recipe">How to Seed a Pomegranate</a>. (Tori&#8217;s post also includes instructions for juicing a pomegranate &#8211; don&#8217;t go that far here, for this salad you want to keep the seeds whole.)</p>
<p>Place kale, spinach and&nbsp;watercress&nbsp;in a large salad bowl and toss to mix. Pour mustard vinaigrette over the top&nbsp;and toss again so the greens are well coated with&nbsp;the dressing. Add the almonds, pomegranate or cranberries, parmesan and onion. Toss to combine all ingredients and serve straight away.</p>
<p><a name="mustardvinaigrette"></a></p>
<p><strong>Mustard Vinaigrette</strong></p>
<p>Makes a little over&nbsp;⅓ cup</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> lemon, juiced (around 1½ tablespoons lemon juice)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dijon mustard</li>
<li>2 teaspoons white wine vinegar</li>
<li>¼ cup olive oil</li>
<li>pinch each of&nbsp;salt and pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar,&nbsp;(ensure the lid is properly secured,)&nbsp;and shake well to combine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orange, kale, carrot &#038; tofu salad</title>
		<link>/2014/12/15/2014-11-25-orange-kale-carrot-tofu-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 05:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/12/15/2014-11-25-orange-kale-carrot-tofu-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">Summer has arrived and doesn't the warmer weather just make it so much easier to eat well?!&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">Here's another idea for a refreshing and tasty salad to enjoy and feel good about.&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">To my readers in the Northern hemisphere, the key fruit and vegetables: oranges, carrots and leafy greens, are in season during winter too, and it's never the wrong time of year to eat well!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/orangetofukalesaladeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Summer has arrived and doesn&#8217;t the warmer weather just make it so much easier to eat well?! <span style="font-size:14px">Here&#8217;s another idea for a refreshing and tasty salad to enjoy and feel good about.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size:14px">To my readers in the Northern hemisphere, the key fruit and vegetables: oranges, carrots and leafy greens, are in season during winter too, and it&#8217;s never the wrong time of year to eat well!</span></p>
<p>This salad is super fresh&nbsp;and simply dressed,&nbsp;it&#8217;s all about letting quality ingredients shine through. So, a few pointers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Save the slightly saggy week-old carrots sitting in the bottom of your fridge&#8217;s crisper for stock or juice and buy (or dig!) a fresh bunch.</li>
<li>Now&#8217;s the time to splash out on good quality tofu;&nbsp;<span style="font-size:14px">you&#8217;re not going to be cooking it or hiding it under any sauces here so</span>&nbsp;it&#8217;s worth an extra couple of dollars for the organic option.</li>
<li>When I used to think of olive oil&nbsp;I thought of Italy, but it turns out Australia produces its own great olive oils here at home. In fact, my favourite: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.homeleighgroveolives.com.au/index.html">Homeleigh Grove&#8217;s</a> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.homeleighgroveolives.com.au/OliveProducts.htm">&#8216;Lowanna&#8217;s Paddock&#8217;</a>, a Robust extra virgin olive oil,&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://www.irvea.org/in-evidenza/nz-sa-2014-awards-ceremony/">was recently awarded first place in a Southern hemisphere international competition</a>! So next time you&#8217;re shopping for olive oil, why not try buying local: if you&#8217;re lucky enough to have a farmers&#8217; market near by, that&#8217;s a good bet, otherwise IGA supermarkets are pretty good at stocking local products too.</li>
</ul>
<p>Did I mention fresh was the key here?&nbsp;I&#8217;m a bit proud of our little veggie garden lately which has become quite productive; you can&#8217;t get much fresher than picked 15 minutes ago!&nbsp;In case you were wondering, here&#8217;s the before photo: spring harvest of homegrown parsley, carrots and kale&#8230;</p>
<p>      <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/img.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This salad is good prepared and served straight away, but if you&#8217;re the oranised type it doesn&#8217;t hurt to let the tofu &#8216;marinate&#8217; with the oranges and herbs in the fridge for a few hours &#8211; just see the guidelines in the recipe below.</p>
<p>If seeds may be an allergen for you or someone you&#8217;re feeding, just leave them off the salad, the fresh carrots will still add a nice crunch. The basil is a nice addition and works well with the other flavours, but I&#8217;ve also made it with just the parsley if I haven&#8217;t had basil on hand.</p>
<p>Serves 5</p>
<ul>
<li>400-500g firm tofu</li>
<li>3 navel oranges (other varieties will work too, just be sure to remove the pips)</li>
<li>Small bunch parsley (approximately 1 cup, loosely packed)</li>
<li>Optional: a few sprigs fresh basil (approximately ½ cup, loosely packed)</li>
<li>1 bunch baby (also known as &#8216;Dutch&#8217;) carrots (regular &#8216;adult&#8217; carrots will work too, if that&#8217;s what&#8217;s available)</li>
<li>1 bunch kale, silverbeet, spinach or other dark leafy green</li>
<li>2 teaspoons poppy seeds</li>
<li>⅓ heaped cup pepitas (pumpkin seeds)</li>
<li>¼ cup olive oil</li>
<li>salt and pepper to taste</li>
</ul>
<p>Cut the tofu into 1 cm &nbsp;(½ inch) cubes and place in a large&nbsp;bowl. Peel the oranges, cut into bite-sized pieces and add to the tofu. Remove the parsley and basil (if using) leaves from their stems. (You can discard the stems).&nbsp;Finely chop the&nbsp;leaves and add to the tofu and oranges. Add just a few pinches each of salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste.&nbsp;Mix well to combine ingredients.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re preparing this in advance stop here, cover and store in the fridge until you&#8217;re just about ready to serve.</p>
<p>Cut the carrots into small pieces (less than 1 cm, or about&nbsp;<span style="font-size:14px">¼ inch in size). Toss through the salad.</span></p>
<p>Remove any tough, fibrous stems from your leafy greens. Coarsely chop or tear the leaves and use these to line serving bowls. Spoon the tofu mix over the greens and&nbsp;drizzle with olive oil (a few teaspoons per serve). Finally, sprinkle with poppy seeds (about&nbsp;<span style="font-size:14px">½ teaspoon per serve) and pepitas (about 1 tablespoon per serve). Important: don&#8217;t add the seeds until you&#8217;re ready to serve the salad, it will keep them nice and crunchy. Enjoy!</span></p>
<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Citrus chia &#8216;frogs eggs&#8217;</title>
		<link>/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 23:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/23/2014-7-27-citrus-chia-frogs-eggs/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p><p><span style="font-size:15px">This snack idea is so simple I almost didn't post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I've had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.</span><span style="font-size:15px">&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Chiagoupeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p><span>&nbsp;</span>DOES NOT CONTAIN FROG</p>
<p>This snack idea is so simple I almost didn&#8217;t post it; doing so feels a bit like writing a recipe for a cup of tea. However, I&#8217;ve had at least five people ask me about this concoction in the space of a week so here it is.<span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>I particularly like chia prepared this way because it&#8217;s an energy source that&#8217;s light enough that I can drink it then proceed to exercise 15 minutes later without feeling remotely ill &#8211; even if that exercise is teaching Body Attack with it&#8217;s tuck-jump-burpees. There are not many foods for which I can say the same.</p>
<p>Now for the credits: idea courtesy of my sister, and the name&#8230; inspired by my mother who came close to convincing her squad of swimmers,&nbsp;using post-exercise nutritional arguments,&nbsp;that she was in fact drinking frogs eggs!</p>
<p>Serves 1</p>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds (any colour)</li>
<li>juice of half a lemon or lime (if you like stronger citrus flavours, add juice from the whole fruit)</li>
<li>300mL water</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar. Secure lid and shake well. Shake a couple of times over the next 5-10 minutes so the chia doesn&#8217;t clump together too densely. Refrigerate or allow to sit for at least 30 minutes and you&#8217;re done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuffed capsicums with parsley pesto</title>
		<link>/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 04:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner's been asking as he shares his suspicions that I'm trying to poison him with the herb, we've been eating that much of it lately! No, I don't have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden.&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Stuffedcapsicum2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner&#8217;s been asking as he shares his suspicions that I&#8217;m trying to poison him with the herb, we&#8217;ve been eating that much of it lately! No, I don&#8217;t have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden. In a battle that&#8217;s been ongoing for several months now, I&#8217;m starting to get the upper hand, in large part thanks to regular batches of <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#parsleypesto">parsley pesto</a>.</p>
<p>I was quite proud of these <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#stuffedcapsicums">stuffed capsicums</a> because they centred around ingredients picked fresh from our garden: the parsley, of course, and also the sage and this delightful harvest of capsicums:</p>
<p>      <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Capsicumparselyharvest1editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Enjoy these stuffed capsicums by themselves or pair with a dose of protein, perhaps eggs or baked fish, for a complete meal.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re entertaining, the capsicums can be prepared and stuffed in advance. Store them in the fridge in an airtight container. Take them out an hour or so before baking so they can come to room temperature, or allow a bit of extra baking time if they&#8217;re still cold.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, omit the walnuts when making the pesto. For a vegan or dairy free version, the pesto is still very good without the parmesan (and I&#8217;ll sometimes make it without cheese if we&#8217;ve run out at home).</p>
<p><a name="stuffedcapsicums"></a></p>
<p><strong>Stuffed Capsicums</strong></p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side or light meal</p>
<ul>
<li>4 capsicums</li>
<li>⅓ cup brown rice</li>
<li>1 brown onion, diced</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, finely diced or chopped</li>
<li>6 leaves fresh sage, finely chopped</li>
<li>¼ cup currants</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>⅓ cup <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#parsleypesto">parsley pesto (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F). Brush a baking dish large enough to hold all the capsicums lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Add the brown rice and ¾ cup water to a saucepan and bring to the boil over a medium heat. Reduce heat to low and simmer until water is absorbed and rice tender, adding a little more water during cooking if needed.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, behead the capsicums (i.e. slice the tops off so you have the capsicum with a &#8216;lid&#8217;). Use a spoon to scoop out the seeds; rinsing under running water can also help clear away loose seeds. Set aside for later use.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a frying pay over medium head and add the onion. Cook, stirring frequently, until onion softens. Add the garlic and sage and cook for another minute or two.</p>
<p>In a bowl stir together the onion mixture, rice, currants, and parsley pesto. Taste and season with salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>Spoon stuffing into the capsicums and top with the lids. If you have left over filling it makes a tasty snack or part of lunch the next day. Arrange capsicums in the baking dish and bake until capsicums are cooked and stuffing is heated through, about 30 minutes. Enjoy!</p>
<p><a name="parsleypesto"></a></p>
<p><strong>Parsley Pesto</strong></p>
<p>Makes about 3/4 cup</p>
<ul>
<li>large bunch flat-leaf parsley</li>
<li>1/4 cup walnuts, toasted</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, unpeeled</li>
<li>3-6 tablespoons olive oil (exact quantity will depend on how much parsley you have and on the blender you&#8217;re using).</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>1/4 cup grated parmesan</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F) and roast garlic for about 20 minutes, until tender.</p>
<p>Add parsley and 2-3 tablespoons of olive oil to a blender or small food processor (I&#8217;ve found my stick blender works best). Process until finely chopped and if parsley does not blend well add more oil. You may also need to stop the blender and scrape down the sides.</p>
<p>Peel the garlic and add it, the walnuts and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Process until you have a paste-like consistency.</p>
<p>Add the parmesan and process briefly to combine. Taste and adjust seasoning as needed.</p>
<p>This will keep stored in the fridge for about a week. The colour may darken a little but it still tastes just as good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wild rice &#038; quinoa pilaf with baked ricotta</title>
		<link>/2014/07/17/2014-7-15-wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 11:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/07/17/2014-7-15-wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><em><span>"It was a dark and stormy night during a miserably cold winter. Fortunately, thanks to Fresh &#38; delish, they had the cosiest comfort food ever to warm them."</span></em><br /><br /><span style="font-size:15px">Okay, so please keep reading to discover that my culinary skills really are better than my somewhat lacking literary talents. This is absolutely one of my favourite meals for a cold stormy night; pair it with some warm mulled wine and you're all set to beat the winter chills.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/ricottaandpilaf1editedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p><em><span>&#8220;It was a dark and stormy night during a miserably cold winter. Fortunately, thanks to Fresh &amp; delish, they had the cosiest comfort food ever to warm them.&#8221;</span></em></p>
<p><span>Okay, so please keep reading to discover that my culinary skills really are better than my somewhat lacking literary talents. This is absolutely one of my favourite meals for a cold stormy night; pair it with some warm mulled wine and you&#8217;re all set to beat the winter chills.</span></p>
<p><span>The <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/15/wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta#wildricequinoapilaf">wild rice &amp; quinoa pilaf</a> is based on a recipe out of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/1000-Gluten-Free-Recipes/dp/B00464EAVG%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3DB00464EAVG">1000 Gluten-Free Recipes</a>, but I&#8217;ve been making the <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/15/wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta#bakedricotta">baked ricotta</a> long enough that I can&#8217;t recall where the idea came from to properly acknowledge it. The ricotta and pilaf can also be made separately as accompaniments to other dishes, but the combination is my epitome of comfort food.</span></p>
<p><span>For this meal I usually get the rice cooking, then prepare the ricotta, and move the pilaf and ricotta to the oven at about the same time. Fresh ricotta has a very short shelf life so don&#8217;t buy it more than a day in advance or it may go sour.</span></p>
<p><span>For a nut free version, simply skip the almonds.</span></p>
<p><a name="wildricequinoapilaf"></a></p>
<p><strong><span>Wild rice and quinoa pilaf</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Serves 4-5 as a side</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>3/4 cup wild rice</span></li>
<li><span>3/4 cup quinoa (black or red is most visually appealing, but all varieties work equally well in terms of flavour)</span></li>
<li><span>3 cups vegetable stock (powdered is okay, just start with less powder than suggested as it is often very salty)</span></li>
<li><span>1/4 cup dried cranberries</span></li>
<li><span>1/4 cup sultanas</span></li>
<li><span>1 tablespoon olive oil</span></li>
<li><span>1/2 cup flaked or slivered almonds, toasted</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>Preheat oven to 180˚C. Combine wild rice and stock in a saucepan and simmer, covered, over a medium heat for 20 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span>If serving with baked ricotta, prepare that now then place in the oven at the same time as the pilaf.</span></p>
<p><span>Brush a cast iron or ceramic baking dish with olive oil.</span></p>
<p><span>Add the quinoa and dried fruit to the wild rice and stock, and stir to combine. Transfer mixture to the baking dish. Cover with a lid if available, otherwise with alfoil pricked in a few places to let excess steam out.</span></p>
<p><span>Bake until rice and quinoa are tender and liquid is absorbed, 45-60 minutes. If the dish dries out before the rice and quinoa are fully cooked just add a little more stock or water.</span></p>
<p><span>Serve spooned over the baked ricotta, and scatter almonds over the top.</span></p>
<p><a name="bakedricotta"></a></p>
<p><strong><span>Baked ricotta</span></strong></p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>500g ricotta</li>
<li><span>2 tablespoons olive oil</span></li>
<li><span>2-4 teaspoons dried herbs or 2-4 tablespoons fresh finely chopped herbs*</span></li>
<li><span>Pinch of pepper</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;*Feel free to try different combinations of herbs and spices depending on what you&#8217;re serving the ricotta with. Personally I&#8217;m a fan of Scarborough Fair&#8217;s parsley, sage, rosemary and thyme, which pairs well with the pilaf. For some other ideas, how about oregano and basil ricotta topped with <a target="_blank" href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/30/spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes#tomatosauce">tomato sauce</a>? Or mixing some toasted cumin and coriander seeds and a little ground cinnamon into the ricotta and serving with a <a target="_blank" href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf#chickpeatagine">chickpea tagine</a>? Perhaps replace the cinnamon with ground cloves or cardamon and pair with an indian curry? The possibilities are endless, and baked ricotta is versatile enough that it really is very hard to ruin.</p>
<p><span>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F) and brush a small (around 1-1.2 L) baking dish with olive oil.</span></p>
<p><span>Wrap ricotta in paper towel or cheesecloth and squeeze out any excess liquid. Transfer to a mixing bowl and add pepper and dried or chopped herbs. Mix well to combine. Taste and adjust seasoning if needed; I like to add a little black pepper but find the cheese generally doesn&#8217;t need any added salt.</span></p>
<p>Spoon ricotta into prepared baking dish and use the back of a dessert spoon to press down and flatten out until it is evenly spread over the dish. Transfer to the oven and bake until the top is a light golden-brown colour, about 45-60 minutes. Cut into slices and serve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; herb cornbread</title>
		<link>/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 03:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who's had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn't want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That's where this cornbread comes in.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/cornbread_edited_compressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who&#8217;s had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn&#8217;t want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That&#8217;s where this cornbread comes in. I have lost track of the number of times I&#8217;ve read an introduction to a recipe for gluten-free baked goods along the lines of &#8220;while other gluten-free recipes may turn out too dense, dry and crumbly or tasting of cardboard, this one actually works!&#8221; only to discover that no, that recipe did not work and was in fact so bad the result ended up in the bin. Again. Hence my delight (bordering on astonishment) when this one did actually work! And it&#8217;s really good! So good that my non-coeliac partner will choose this over his (glutenated) toast, when I&#8217;m willing to share.</p>
<p>The recipe is based on one out of The Australian Coeliac, the magazine produced by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/index.html">Coeliac Australia</a>, which I&#8217;ve modified to suit my tastes, namely by using more fresh herbs, less sugar.</p>
<p>Serves 6-8 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>scant cup gluten-free flour*</li>
<li>1/3 cup polenta</li>
<li>1 teaspoon xanthum gum</li>
<li>1 tablespoon caster sugar</li>
<li>1 tablespoon gluten-free baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 cup milk</li>
<li>1 egg, lightly beaten</li>
<li>2 tablespoons canola oil</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly grated parmesan cheese</li>
<li>2/3 cup freshly grated cheddar cheese</li>
<li>6 shallots, finely sliced</li>
<li>1/4 cup fresh herbs, finely chopped (I usually use parsley with one or two others such as basil or thyme, depending on what I have on hand and what soup I&#8217;m making)</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>*I use the brown rice gluten-free flour mix suggested in&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gluten-Free-Baking-Classics-Annalise-Roberts/dp/1572840994%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1572840994">Gluten-Free Baking Classics</a>,</em><span>&nbsp;by Annalise Roberts: 6 parts brown rice flour : 2 parts potato starch : 1 part tapioca starch.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Preheat oven to 220˚C (425 F). Grease a 20cm square baking tin.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Combine dry ingredients (flour, polenta, xanthum gum, sugar, baking powder, salt and pepper) in a large mixing bowl and mix well.</p>
<p>In a separate bowl, whisk together the wet ingredients (milk, egg and canola oil).</p>
<p>Add wet ingredients to the dry and whisk until a smooth batter is formed. Stir in the cheeses, shallots and herbs until just combined.</p>
<p>Pour into baking tin and bake for about 25 minutes, until top is golden and a skewer comes out clean. Check the cornbread after around 15-20 minutes &#8211; if the top is golden and you want to prevent it darkening further while the cornbread cooks through, cover the pan with foil, pricked in a few places to let out excess steam.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Allow to cool in the pan, and serve warm or at room temperature.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ricotta-stuffed mushrooms</title>
		<link>/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 03:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hors d'oeuvres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>If you're in Australia at the moment, chances are you've got a barbecue or three coming up. If you're in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Ricottastuffedmushroomseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re in Australia at the moment, chances are you&#8217;ve got a barbecue or three coming up. If you&#8217;re in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</p>
<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been using largish button mushrooms in this recipe, as they&#8217;re the perfect size for sharing.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re after meal-sized servings though, try using portobello mushrooms instead.</p>
<p>These mushrooms can be baked, grilled or barbecued &#8211; the preparation is all the same.</p>
<p>For a super-quick variant, just mix the ricotta and sun-dried tomatoes with salt and pepper to taste, perhaps add some dry herbs if they&#8217;re handy, pile on top of portobello mushrooms and add to the barbie.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts.</p>
<p>Makes 12 pieces</p>
<p>12 medium-large button mushrooms (or 3-4 portobello mushrooms)</p>
<p>2 cloves garlic, finely chopped</p>
<p>1 tablespoon olive oil</p>
<p>300g ricotta</p>
<p>1/4 cup sun-dried tomatoes, drained and chopped</p>
<p>2 tablespoons pine nuts, toasted</p>
<p>2 tablespoons fresh oregano and/or thyme leaves, finely chopped</p>
<p>salt and pepper</p>
<p>If baking, preheat oven to 180˚C (350F).</p>
<p>Remove stems from the mushrooms and coarsely chop, discarding any woody bits. To remove the stem of a mushroom: hold the mushroom in one hand and use your other hand to pinch the stem, squeezing so the stem splits. Pinch the two halves of the stem together and squeeze so it&#8217;s now split into four pieces. Now twist the stem, and it should come easily away from the mushroom.</p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a small skillet over medium heat. Add mushroom stems and garlic and sauté until garlic is fragrant and stems are lightly browned.</p>
<p>Wrap ricotta in paper towels or cheese cloth and squeeze to remove excess liquid.</p>
<p>Combine mushroom stems, ricotta, sun-dried tomatoes, pine nuts and fresh herbs in a bowl and mix to combine. Season with a few pinches of salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>If using portobello mushrooms, sprinkle the underside of the mushrooms lightly with salt and pepper. Skip this step if using button mushrooms (I think it&#8217;s too fiddly and you&#8217;ve already seasoned the stuffing).</p>
<p>Place mushrooms on a baking tray, skin-side facing down, and fill with the ricotta stuffing. Your mushrooms are now ready to cook, but cooking time will depend on the size of your mushrooms and method of cooking. Small mushrooms will cook in 10 minutes under a grill, portobello mushrooms may take 30-40 mins to bake. As a guide, check button mushrooms after 10-15 minutes, and portobello mushrooms after 20-30 minutes. The mushrooms will be ready when the ricotta is golden-brown and the mushroom is heated through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Banana egg flip</title>
		<link>/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 10:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/12/07/2013-11-25-banana-eggflip/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It's something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/bananaeggflipeditedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is one of my favourite post-workout snacks. It&#8217;s something of a cross between an egg flip and a banana smoothie and has good doses of both carbohydrates and protein to assist in recovery. I like to make it in two flavours: chocolate or vanilla.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll make this in the morning, keep it in the fridge at work and find it&#8217;s still fine for evening consumption.&nbsp;</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the LSA. For a dairy/lactose free option, replace the milk with soy milk or other non-dairy milk and likewise skip the yoghurt or use a non-dairy alternative.</p>
<p>Makes 1 large serving</p>
<ul>
<li>1 banana</li>
<li>2 eggs</li>
<li>1/2 cup milk</li>
<li>2 tablespoons natural or greek yoghurt</li>
<li>1 tablespoon LSA</li>
<li>2 teaspoons cocoa powder or 1/2 teaspoon vanilla essence (adjust to taste)</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a blender and blend until smooth. How easy is that?!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
