<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sides &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/sides/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 05:40:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tegan Salad</title>
		<link>/2015/02/23/2015-1-1-tegan-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/02/23/2015-1-1-tegan-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">I tend to get a little concerned when I hear the 'vegetarian'&#160;conversation&#160;going on in the background while I'm cooking. It goes something like this:&#160;my partner being quizzed by our dinner guest along the lines of "so are you vegetarian too?", "do you always eat vegetarian meals?", "do you mind not eating meat at home?", "what about protein?",&#160;etc., etc. Fast forward an hour or two and said guest has not only complemented the meal but&#160;scraped his plate clean and even volunteered to do the washing up (actions speak louder than words)...&#160;I think maybe I've changed someone's mind on vegetarian cooking!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/img.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>I tend to get a little concerned when I hear the &#8216;vegetarian&#8217; conversation going on in the background while I&#8217;m cooking. It goes something like this: my partner being quizzed by our dinner guest along the lines of &#8220;so are you vegetarian too?&#8221;, &#8220;do you always eat vegetarian meals?&#8221;, &#8220;do you mind not eating meat at home?&#8221;, &#8220;what about protein?&#8221;, etc., etc. Fast forward an hour or two and said guest has not only complemented the meal but scraped his plate clean and even volunteered to do the washing up (actions speak louder than words)&#8230; I think maybe I&#8217;ve changed someone&#8217;s mind on vegetarian cooking!</p>
<p>This recipe came about by combining a mango and halloumi salad suggestion from my good friend Tegan, with a mango and avocado salad recipe from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Joy-Cooking-All-About-Vegetarian/dp/B0002Y0SII%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3DB0002Y0SII" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joy of Cooking: All About Vegetarian Cooking</a> by Irma Rombauer et al., along with some tweaks of my own. If you&#8217;ve tried my recipes before, hopefully you&#8217;ve learned that even (or especially) when you read an ingredients list and the words &#8220;unlikely combination&#8221; come to mind, the result is going to be good. If you&#8217;re new to my blog then trust me, this is worth being a little adventurous!</p>
<p>I often include eggs with the salad to turn in into a complete meal, but I also like serving it without the eggs alongside panfried fish or to add a bit of &#8216;wow&#8217; factor to a spread. The number of eggs is also easily varied according to appetite: after something slightly lighter? make it 1 egg per person, feeding a hungry man after a big training session? pile on some extra eggs and maybe add a side with more carbs.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the macadamias. For a vegan and dairy/lactose free salad, leave out the eggs and halloumi and the resulting mango and avocado salad is still a great combination!</p>
<p>Serves 4</p>
<ul>
<li>½ cup macadamia nuts</li>
<li>1 lemon, juiced (around 3 tablespoons lemon juice)</li>
<li>2 avocados</li>
<li>2 small-medium mangoes or 1 large</li>
<li>½ red onion</li>
<li>2 or 3 tablespoons olive oil (use 3 tablespoons if you&#8217;re including eggs, otherwise just use 2)</li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>¼ cup fresh basil, finely chopped</li>
<li>4 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>8 eggs (optional)</li>
<li>200g halloumi</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 160˚C (320 F). Coarsely chop the macadamias then spread on a baking tray. Bake in oven until macadamias are fragrant and lightly toasted. If your oven is preheated this will only take 3-5 minutes, although they may need longer if the oven&#8217;s still heating up. Keep a close eye on them, nuts will generally go from raw to burnt very easily if you get distracted. Once the macadamias are toasted set them aside until you&#8217;re ready to serve.</p>
<p>Place half the lemon juice in a medium-sized bowl. Slice the avocados lengthwise and remove the stones. Score flesh into approximately 1cm pieces then scoop it away from the skin and place in the bowl of lemon juice. Toss to coat the avocado with lemon juice &#8211; this will help prevent browning (which is quite harmless but aesthetically not very pleasing).</p>
<p>Cut the mango(es) into approximately 1 cm pieces and add to the avocado. Peel and finely slice the red onion; add it to the mango and avocado then toss to combine.</p>
<p>Make the dressing: combine 2 tablespoon olive oil, the remaining lemon juice, finely chopped basil and a pinch each of salt and pepper in a jar and shake to combine.</p>
<p>Divide baby spinach between serving plates and spoon avocado and mango mixture over the top.</p>
<p>If serving with eggs: depending on your frying pan you may need to cook the eggs in a few batches. Heat the remaining tablespoon (or for batches, portion there-of) of olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Keeping the medium heat, fry the eggs for a 2-3 minutes on each side until light golden and cooked through. Serve alongside the salad and season with a little salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>Finally, cook the halloumi. This is very quick so I do it last after I&#8217;ve cooked the eggs. Use the frying pan from the eggs that&#8217;s still hot, or heat your frying pan over a hot stove then turn the heat down to medium. Placing halloumi into an already hot pan will ensure it forms a delicious golden crust while melting on the inside (whereas if it cooks too slowly you may end up with a blob of molten cheese in your pan). There&#8217;s generally enough fat in the halloumi that it doesn&#8217;t need extra oil for cooking, especially if you&#8217;re using a non-stick frying pan. Cook over a medium heat for about 1 minute on each side until halloumi is golden brown then server over the salad.</p>
<p>Give the dressing you made another shake to ensure it&#8217;s well mixed then drizzle over the salad. Sprinkle with macadamia nuts and you&#8217;re good to go. Happy Dinner! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.4/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crunchy mixed greens with mustard vinaigrette</title>
		<link>/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 01:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/14/2015-1-6-crunchy-mixed-greens-with-mustard-vinaigrette/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px"><em>"There might not be enough food... the boys are coming and&#160;they eat A LOT"</em> -&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">Lil' Sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch. Despite being fairly confident that&#160;</span><span style="font-size:14px">there would be plenty of food</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;I agreed to add an extra dish,</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;opting</span><span style="font-size:14px">&#160;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&#160;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&#160;(Admittedly&#160;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&#160;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&#160;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img-5.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<figure>
<blockquote><p>
    <span>&#8220;</span>There might not be enough food&#8230; the boys are coming and they eat A LOT.<span>&#8221;</span><br />
  </blockquote><figcaption class="source">&mdash; Lil&#8217; sis reviewing my plans for Christmas lunch.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Despite being fairly confident that&nbsp;there would be plenty of food&nbsp;I agreed to add an extra dish,&nbsp;opting&nbsp;for a leafy salad to complement the already substantial meal.&nbsp;As it turns out, we were still polishing off the left overs three days later!&nbsp;(Admittedly&nbsp;left-overs <em>are</em> almost compulsory following Christmas lunch.) In this case it definitely&nbsp;worked out for the best because this creation is really very good&nbsp;(am I allowed to say that about my own recipe?)</p>
<p>Back home and through the process of testing the recipe this salad&nbsp;has rapidly become a favourite. Only thing is, there are two versions and I can&#8217;t decide which I like best, so I&#8217;ve included both options and you can choose for yourself.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The question before you is this: pomegranate or cranberries? The pomegranate seeds are refreshing and add a nice crunch. The cranberries are sweeter and slightly chewy. I like both versions. I&#8217;d suggest the pomegranate&nbsp;as a nice refreshing choice&nbsp;on a&nbsp;warm day, and the cranberries when you&#8217;re looking to bring a little more sweetness to the meal. Dried cranberries are also typically easier to come by than fresh pomegranates.</p>
<p><span style="font-size:14px">I haven&#8217;t included rocket in my leafy greens.&nbsp;Personally I don&#8217;t like rocket&nbsp;&#8211;&nbsp;I find it too hot &#8211;&nbsp;while the watercress here is just a little peppery.&nbsp;If you are a fan of rocket&nbsp;I suspect if would work well in this salad, and I always encourage experimentation when cooking.</span></p>
<p>For a nut free version, skip the almonds. It won&#8217;t be as crunchy but the combination of flavours should still survive. For a vegan or dairy/lactose-free alternative, omit the parmesan.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 cups baby kale</li>
<li>2 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>1 cup watercress leaves, removed from stems</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> cup almonds</li>
<li>1 pomegranate or ½ cup dried cranberries</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> cup shaved parmesan</li>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> red onion, finely sliced or diced</li>
<li><a href="#"><span style="font-size:14px">⅓ cup m</span>ustard Vinaigrette (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If using a&nbsp;pomegranate, start by seeding the fruit (otherwise, skip straight to the next paragraph). Tori&nbsp;Avey provides some great instructions explaining&nbsp;<a target="_blank" href="http://toriavey.com/toris-kitchen/2011/09/how-to-seed-a-pomegranate/#recipe">How to Seed a Pomegranate</a>. (Tori&#8217;s post also includes instructions for juicing a pomegranate &#8211; don&#8217;t go that far here, for this salad you want to keep the seeds whole.)</p>
<p>Place kale, spinach and&nbsp;watercress&nbsp;in a large salad bowl and toss to mix. Pour mustard vinaigrette over the top&nbsp;and toss again so the greens are well coated with&nbsp;the dressing. Add the almonds, pomegranate or cranberries, parmesan and onion. Toss to combine all ingredients and serve straight away.</p>
<p><a name="mustardvinaigrette"></a></p>
<p><strong>Mustard Vinaigrette</strong></p>
<p>Makes a little over&nbsp;⅓ cup</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-size:14px">½</span> lemon, juiced (around 1½ tablespoons lemon juice)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dijon mustard</li>
<li>2 teaspoons white wine vinegar</li>
<li>¼ cup olive oil</li>
<li>pinch each of&nbsp;salt and pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients in a jar,&nbsp;(ensure the lid is properly secured,)&nbsp;and shake well to combine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuffed capsicums with parsley pesto</title>
		<link>/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 04:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner's been asking as he shares his suspicions that I'm trying to poison him with the herb, we've been eating that much of it lately! No, I don't have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden.&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Stuffedcapsicum2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner&#8217;s been asking as he shares his suspicions that I&#8217;m trying to poison him with the herb, we&#8217;ve been eating that much of it lately! No, I don&#8217;t have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden. In a battle that&#8217;s been ongoing for several months now, I&#8217;m starting to get the upper hand, in large part thanks to regular batches of <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#parsleypesto">parsley pesto</a>.</p>
<p>I was quite proud of these <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#stuffedcapsicums">stuffed capsicums</a> because they centred around ingredients picked fresh from our garden: the parsley, of course, and also the sage and this delightful harvest of capsicums:</p>
<p>      <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Capsicumparselyharvest1editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Enjoy these stuffed capsicums by themselves or pair with a dose of protein, perhaps eggs or baked fish, for a complete meal.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re entertaining, the capsicums can be prepared and stuffed in advance. Store them in the fridge in an airtight container. Take them out an hour or so before baking so they can come to room temperature, or allow a bit of extra baking time if they&#8217;re still cold.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, omit the walnuts when making the pesto. For a vegan or dairy free version, the pesto is still very good without the parmesan (and I&#8217;ll sometimes make it without cheese if we&#8217;ve run out at home).</p>
<p><a name="stuffedcapsicums"></a></p>
<p><strong>Stuffed Capsicums</strong></p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side or light meal</p>
<ul>
<li>4 capsicums</li>
<li>⅓ cup brown rice</li>
<li>1 brown onion, diced</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, finely diced or chopped</li>
<li>6 leaves fresh sage, finely chopped</li>
<li>¼ cup currants</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>⅓ cup <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/27/stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto#parsleypesto">parsley pesto (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F). Brush a baking dish large enough to hold all the capsicums lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Add the brown rice and ¾ cup water to a saucepan and bring to the boil over a medium heat. Reduce heat to low and simmer until water is absorbed and rice tender, adding a little more water during cooking if needed.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, behead the capsicums (i.e. slice the tops off so you have the capsicum with a &#8216;lid&#8217;). Use a spoon to scoop out the seeds; rinsing under running water can also help clear away loose seeds. Set aside for later use.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a frying pay over medium head and add the onion. Cook, stirring frequently, until onion softens. Add the garlic and sage and cook for another minute or two.</p>
<p>In a bowl stir together the onion mixture, rice, currants, and parsley pesto. Taste and season with salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>Spoon stuffing into the capsicums and top with the lids. If you have left over filling it makes a tasty snack or part of lunch the next day. Arrange capsicums in the baking dish and bake until capsicums are cooked and stuffing is heated through, about 30 minutes. Enjoy!</p>
<p><a name="parsleypesto"></a></p>
<p><strong>Parsley Pesto</strong></p>
<p>Makes about 3/4 cup</p>
<ul>
<li>large bunch flat-leaf parsley</li>
<li>1/4 cup walnuts, toasted</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, unpeeled</li>
<li>3-6 tablespoons olive oil (exact quantity will depend on how much parsley you have and on the blender you&#8217;re using).</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>1/4 cup grated parmesan</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F) and roast garlic for about 20 minutes, until tender.</p>
<p>Add parsley and 2-3 tablespoons of olive oil to a blender or small food processor (I&#8217;ve found my stick blender works best). Process until finely chopped and if parsley does not blend well add more oil. You may also need to stop the blender and scrape down the sides.</p>
<p>Peel the garlic and add it, the walnuts and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Process until you have a paste-like consistency.</p>
<p>Add the parmesan and process briefly to combine. Taste and adjust seasoning as needed.</p>
<p>This will keep stored in the fridge for about a week. The colour may darken a little but it still tastes just as good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wild rice &#038; quinoa pilaf with baked ricotta</title>
		<link>/2014/07/17/2014-7-15-wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 11:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/07/17/2014-7-15-wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><em><span>"It was a dark and stormy night during a miserably cold winter. Fortunately, thanks to Fresh &#38; delish, they had the cosiest comfort food ever to warm them."</span></em><br /><br /><span style="font-size:15px">Okay, so please keep reading to discover that my culinary skills really are better than my somewhat lacking literary talents. This is absolutely one of my favourite meals for a cold stormy night; pair it with some warm mulled wine and you're all set to beat the winter chills.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/ricottaandpilaf1editedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p><em><span>&#8220;It was a dark and stormy night during a miserably cold winter. Fortunately, thanks to Fresh &amp; delish, they had the cosiest comfort food ever to warm them.&#8221;</span></em></p>
<p><span>Okay, so please keep reading to discover that my culinary skills really are better than my somewhat lacking literary talents. This is absolutely one of my favourite meals for a cold stormy night; pair it with some warm mulled wine and you&#8217;re all set to beat the winter chills.</span></p>
<p><span>The <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/15/wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta#wildricequinoapilaf">wild rice &amp; quinoa pilaf</a> is based on a recipe out of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/1000-Gluten-Free-Recipes/dp/B00464EAVG%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3DB00464EAVG">1000 Gluten-Free Recipes</a>, but I&#8217;ve been making the <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2014/7/15/wild-rice-quinoa-pilaf-with-baked-ricotta#bakedricotta">baked ricotta</a> long enough that I can&#8217;t recall where the idea came from to properly acknowledge it. The ricotta and pilaf can also be made separately as accompaniments to other dishes, but the combination is my epitome of comfort food.</span></p>
<p><span>For this meal I usually get the rice cooking, then prepare the ricotta, and move the pilaf and ricotta to the oven at about the same time. Fresh ricotta has a very short shelf life so don&#8217;t buy it more than a day in advance or it may go sour.</span></p>
<p><span>For a nut free version, simply skip the almonds.</span></p>
<p><a name="wildricequinoapilaf"></a></p>
<p><strong><span>Wild rice and quinoa pilaf</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Serves 4-5 as a side</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>3/4 cup wild rice</span></li>
<li><span>3/4 cup quinoa (black or red is most visually appealing, but all varieties work equally well in terms of flavour)</span></li>
<li><span>3 cups vegetable stock (powdered is okay, just start with less powder than suggested as it is often very salty)</span></li>
<li><span>1/4 cup dried cranberries</span></li>
<li><span>1/4 cup sultanas</span></li>
<li><span>1 tablespoon olive oil</span></li>
<li><span>1/2 cup flaked or slivered almonds, toasted</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>Preheat oven to 180˚C. Combine wild rice and stock in a saucepan and simmer, covered, over a medium heat for 20 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span>If serving with baked ricotta, prepare that now then place in the oven at the same time as the pilaf.</span></p>
<p><span>Brush a cast iron or ceramic baking dish with olive oil.</span></p>
<p><span>Add the quinoa and dried fruit to the wild rice and stock, and stir to combine. Transfer mixture to the baking dish. Cover with a lid if available, otherwise with alfoil pricked in a few places to let excess steam out.</span></p>
<p><span>Bake until rice and quinoa are tender and liquid is absorbed, 45-60 minutes. If the dish dries out before the rice and quinoa are fully cooked just add a little more stock or water.</span></p>
<p><span>Serve spooned over the baked ricotta, and scatter almonds over the top.</span></p>
<p><a name="bakedricotta"></a></p>
<p><strong><span>Baked ricotta</span></strong></p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>500g ricotta</li>
<li><span>2 tablespoons olive oil</span></li>
<li><span>2-4 teaspoons dried herbs or 2-4 tablespoons fresh finely chopped herbs*</span></li>
<li><span>Pinch of pepper</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;*Feel free to try different combinations of herbs and spices depending on what you&#8217;re serving the ricotta with. Personally I&#8217;m a fan of Scarborough Fair&#8217;s parsley, sage, rosemary and thyme, which pairs well with the pilaf. For some other ideas, how about oregano and basil ricotta topped with <a target="_blank" href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/30/spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes#tomatosauce">tomato sauce</a>? Or mixing some toasted cumin and coriander seeds and a little ground cinnamon into the ricotta and serving with a <a target="_blank" href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf#chickpeatagine">chickpea tagine</a>? Perhaps replace the cinnamon with ground cloves or cardamon and pair with an indian curry? The possibilities are endless, and baked ricotta is versatile enough that it really is very hard to ruin.</p>
<p><span>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F) and brush a small (around 1-1.2 L) baking dish with olive oil.</span></p>
<p><span>Wrap ricotta in paper towel or cheesecloth and squeeze out any excess liquid. Transfer to a mixing bowl and add pepper and dried or chopped herbs. Mix well to combine. Taste and adjust seasoning if needed; I like to add a little black pepper but find the cheese generally doesn&#8217;t need any added salt.</span></p>
<p>Spoon ricotta into prepared baking dish and use the back of a dessert spoon to press down and flatten out until it is evenly spread over the dish. Transfer to the oven and bake until the top is a light golden-brown colour, about 45-60 minutes. Cut into slices and serve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; herb cornbread</title>
		<link>/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 03:44:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/05/30/2013-4-23-cheese-herb-cornbread/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who's had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn't want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That's where this cornbread comes in.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/cornbread_edited_compressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Winter is not my favourite time of year, but there are many things I do like about the cold weather: fluffy blankets, oversized jumpers, hot chocolate and warming soup being among them. The problem is what a coeliac, who&#8217;s had little success with gluten-free baking and doesn&#8217;t want to spend a small fortune on average-at-best gluten-free bread every week, have to accompany her soup? That&#8217;s where this cornbread comes in. I have lost track of the number of times I&#8217;ve read an introduction to a recipe for gluten-free baked goods along the lines of &#8220;while other gluten-free recipes may turn out too dense, dry and crumbly or tasting of cardboard, this one actually works!&#8221; only to discover that no, that recipe did not work and was in fact so bad the result ended up in the bin. Again. Hence my delight (bordering on astonishment) when this one did actually work! And it&#8217;s really good! So good that my non-coeliac partner will choose this over his (glutenated) toast, when I&#8217;m willing to share.</p>
<p>The recipe is based on one out of The Australian Coeliac, the magazine produced by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/index.html">Coeliac Australia</a>, which I&#8217;ve modified to suit my tastes, namely by using more fresh herbs, less sugar.</p>
<p>Serves 6-8 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>scant cup gluten-free flour*</li>
<li>1/3 cup polenta</li>
<li>1 teaspoon xanthum gum</li>
<li>1 tablespoon caster sugar</li>
<li>1 tablespoon gluten-free baking powder</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 cup milk</li>
<li>1 egg, lightly beaten</li>
<li>2 tablespoons canola oil</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly grated parmesan cheese</li>
<li>2/3 cup freshly grated cheddar cheese</li>
<li>6 shallots, finely sliced</li>
<li>1/4 cup fresh herbs, finely chopped (I usually use parsley with one or two others such as basil or thyme, depending on what I have on hand and what soup I&#8217;m making)</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>*I use the brown rice gluten-free flour mix suggested in&nbsp;<em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Gluten-Free-Baking-Classics-Annalise-Roberts/dp/1572840994%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1572840994">Gluten-Free Baking Classics</a>,</em><span>&nbsp;by Annalise Roberts: 6 parts brown rice flour : 2 parts potato starch : 1 part tapioca starch.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Preheat oven to 220˚C (425 F). Grease a 20cm square baking tin.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Combine dry ingredients (flour, polenta, xanthum gum, sugar, baking powder, salt and pepper) in a large mixing bowl and mix well.</p>
<p>In a separate bowl, whisk together the wet ingredients (milk, egg and canola oil).</p>
<p>Add wet ingredients to the dry and whisk until a smooth batter is formed. Stir in the cheeses, shallots and herbs until just combined.</p>
<p>Pour into baking tin and bake for about 25 minutes, until top is golden and a skewer comes out clean. Check the cornbread after around 15-20 minutes &#8211; if the top is golden and you want to prevent it darkening further while the cornbread cooks through, cover the pan with foil, pricked in a few places to let out excess steam.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Allow to cool in the pan, and serve warm or at room temperature.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roast eggplant puree</title>
		<link>/2013/05/01/2013-4-28-roast-eggplant-puree/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 11:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/05/01/2013-4-28-roast-eggplant-puree/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This isn't quite quick, due to the cooking time required, but it is dead easy to make, and oh so yummy. It's a great option as a side when you're preparing something else which is a bit involved, as this will take little effort from you and can cook in the mean time.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/eggplantpureeeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t quite quick, due to the cooking time required, but it is dead easy to make, and oh so yummy. It&#8217;s a great option as a side when you&#8217;re preparing something else which is a bit involved, as this will take little effort from you and can cook in the mean time.</p>
<p>You could also try serving this sprinkled with pine nuts and/or goat&#8217;s cheese.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large eggplant, cut in half lengthways</li>
<li>1 large red capsicum</li>
<li>1 head garlic (unpeeled)</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh basil, finely chopped</li>
<li>2-3 tablespoons balsamic vinegar</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>2 cups baby spinach</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 200˚C (390 F).</p>
<p>Sprinkle cut sides of eggplant with salt and set aside, cut side down, to drain for at least 30 minutes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, brush garlic lightly with olive oil and place it and the capsicum on a baking tray and cook until the skin on the capsicum has blistered and the garlic is tender, about 30 minutes. Turn the capsicum during cooking so the skin blisters on all sides. Set garlic and capsicum aside until cool enough to handle.</p>
<p>Rinse eggplant well and pat dry then brush the cut sides with olive oil. Place eggplant on a baking tray, cut sides face-down. Bake until eggplant is very tender (the skin will also be slightly crinkly), about 30-40 minutes.</p>
<p>Squeeze garlic out of its peel and into a bowl. Peel and seed capsicum, pat dry and finely dice, then add to the garlic. Peel eggplant skin away from the flesh (or if it&#8217;s not coming away easily, scoop flesh out with a metal spoon). Finely dice eggplant flesh and add to the bowl. Add the fresh basil, along with the balsamic, 1 tablespoon olive oil and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Adjust the vinegar and seasoning to taste.</p>
<p>Serve warm or at room temperature, spooned over the baby spinach.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fried halloumi with caremalised fennel</title>
		<link>/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 14:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here's one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn't tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/caremalisedfennelhalloumi2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here&#8217;s one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn&#8217;t tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>
<p>Store bought halloumi will work just fine here, but if you&#8217;d like to have a go at making it yourself, the recipe I followed (which worked really well) can be found <a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/Halloumi.html" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;I ordered my cheese making supplies from <a href="http://www.greenlivingaustralia.com.au/" target="_blank">Green Living Australia</a> in Queensland who had fantastically speedy service. Making halloumi requires some patience, but the product is well worth it and it&#8217;s so satisfying to convert a big pot of milk into a tasty block of cheese oneself.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large bulb fennel, trimmed, quartered and cut into 5-10mm thick slices</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil, plus a little extra</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon caraway seeds, toasted and ground</li>
<li>pinch fennel seeds, toasted and ground (just add to the caraway and prepare together)</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried tarragon</li>
<li>1/4 cup white wine (optional)</li>
<li>1/4 cup loosely packed fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
<li>100g halloumi cheese, cut into 5mm thick slices</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat 2 tablespoons olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the fennel, ground spices and tarragon and cook until fennel begins to soften. Add the wine (if using, otherwise just keep cooking as is) and cook until pan is almost dry and fennel is tender and golden. If the pan dries out and fennel browns before cooking through, add a little water.</p>
<p>Transfer fennel to a bowl and toss with lemon juice and fresh herbs.</p>
<p>Rinse out the pan before cooking the halloumi. Unless using a non-stick pan, or if the teflon coating is starting to go, add a little oil to coat the pan. You don&#8217;t need much oil as the halloumi will release its own fat as it cooks. Turn the heat up to high and when the pan is nice and hot add the halloumi slices. Don&#8217;t add the halloumi while the pan is still cool or it will melt into a blob before a nice crust forms. Fry halloumi until light golden on the underside then flip and cook until both sides are light golden. This will only take around 1-2 minutes per side.</p>
<p>Arrange the fennel on plates and serve the fried halloumi atop the fennel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marinated mushroom, fennel and grilled potato salad</title>
		<link>/2013/04/25/2013-4-22-marinated-mushroom-fennel-and-grilled-potato-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 13:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/25/2013-4-22-marinated-mushroom-fennel-and-grilled-potato-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I like to serve this salad as an accompaniment to fish, especially a stronger-flavoured fish like salmon. There's something about the combination of earthy mushrooms and slightly salty potato that just seems like a good match for fish to me. Add the fennel and you've got a nice seasonal salad for Autumn.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/potatomushroomfenneleditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I like to serve this salad as an accompaniment to fish, especially a stronger-flavoured fish like salmon. There&#8217;s something about the combination of earthy mushrooms and slightly salty potato that just seems like a good match for fish to me. Add the fennel and you&#8217;ve got a nice seasonal salad for Autumn.</p>
<p>Gruyère cheese works very well in this dish, but it&#8217;s quite expensive and I don&#8217;t tend to keep it on hand, so I&#8217;ll often just use cheddar which is also tasty.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts and replace the peanut oil with canola oil. For a dairy/lactose-free or vegan salad, omit the cheese.</p>
<p>Serves 3-4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>400g mushrooms, quartered, halved or left whole, depending on size</li>
<li>1 bulb baby fennel, trimmed, quartered, cored and finely sliced</li>
<li>600g potatoes (I really like dutch cream, but any white potato will do)</li>
<li>100g cheddar or gruyère cheese, cut into 1cm cubes</li>
<li>2 tablespoons pine nuts, toasted</li>
<li>2 tablespoons balsamic vinegar</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>peanut oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine the balsamic and olive oil in a medium bowl along with a pinch each of salt and pepper. Add the mushrooms and mix until the mushrooms are well coated with the&nbsp;vinaigrette. Add the fennel, toss to combine and set aside to marinate for at least 30 minutes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, boil the potatoes until just tender &#8211; firm enough that they still retain their shape. You&#8217;ll be cooking them further under the grill so try not to over cook them here. Drain, pat dry and cut into 2cm cubes. Toss with just enough peanut oil to lightly coat the potatoes. Heat grill or broiler (or you can use a hot oven). Spread potatoes on a tray in a single layer and sprinkle lightly with salt. Place under grill or broiler and cook until golden and crispy, 10-15 minutes.</p>
<p>To serve, combine mushroom and fennel with potatoes and cheese, and sprinkle pine nuts over the top.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lemon scented silverbeet with currants</title>
		<link>/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 12:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.​</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/silverbeetlemoncurrants2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.</p>
<p>Serves 2-3 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 bunch silverbeet, rinsed, stems removed and coarsely chopped</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>2 tablespoons currants</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add silverbeet and lemon juice and toss to coat silverbeet with the lemon and oil. I like to add the currants now too, as cooking them with the silverbeet will make them nice and juicy. Cook, stirring frequently, until silverbeet is just wilted, about 5 minutes. Serve immediately.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Broccoli salad</title>
		<link>/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn't like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/broccolisaladeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn&#8217;t like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>
<p>Despite the broccoli, this is actually quite a sweet salad, so keep this in mind when thinking about what to pair it with (perhaps a quiche or grilled fish).</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, just skip the almonds.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 heads broccoli, stems and florets, chopped into bite-size pieces</li>
<li>1/2 cup mayonnaise*</li>
<li>1 scant tablespoon red wine vinegar</li>
<li>2 teaspoons honey</li>
<li>1/4 red onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup dried cranberries</li>
<li>1/2 cup flaked or slivered almonds, toasted</li>
</ul>
<p>*On this occasion I used homemade mayonnaise, which was delicious, but I have made this with store-bought before and that works too. This was my first time making mayonnaise so I haven&#8217;t developed my own version yet, but if you&#8217;re interested, the recipe I followed can be found <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/wordofmouth/2010/jul/01/how-to-make-perfect-mayonnaise" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Steam the broccoli until just tender, you want it to retain some crispness so try and avoid over-cooking. The stems will take a little longer to cook, so I generally start steaming these first, then after a few minutes add the florets and steam for another couple of minutes. When cooked, swirl the broccoli in icy water to chill. This will both stop the cooking and chill it for the salad. Drain and pat dry.</p>
<p>To make the dressing, mix mayonnaise, vinegar and honey together in a small bowl.</p>
<p>Combine broccoli, onion and cranberries. Pour in dressing and toss to coat. Sprinkle the almonds over the top just before serving. (The cranberries and onion have a habit of accumulating in the bottom of a large salad bowl, so take note to scoop these up as you&#8217;re serving the broccoli.)</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
