<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Legumes &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/legumes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 05:40:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Warm Mediterranean rice salad</title>
		<link>/2015/01/08/2014-12-26-warm-mediterranean-rice-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 23:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2015/01/08/2014-12-26-warm-mediterranean-rice-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:14px">Like many cooking enthusiasts&#160;I spent the days leading up to Christmas planning lunch for Christmas day, with little thought given to Christmas eve. "I'll throw something quick together"&#160;I thought. Christmas eve night&#160;arrives and I find my self staying with&#160;my sister, who mentions a mate's helping her out with something and could we feed him too please? Okay, so now I'm in someone else's kitchen, with someone else's pantry and we've got guests for dinner. Oh dear. A quick (read 'frantic') rummage through lil' sis'&#160;supplies and ideas are starting to form. This is what I came up with and it was good enough to warrant photos and a recipe request from lil' sis.</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/img-3.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Like many cooking enthusiasts&nbsp;I spent the days leading up to Christmas planning lunch for Christmas day, with little thought given to Christmas eve. &#8220;I&#8217;ll throw something quick together&#8221;&nbsp;I thought. Christmas eve night&nbsp;arrives and I find my self staying with&nbsp;my sister, who mentions a mate&#8217;s helping her out with something and could we feed him too please? Okay, so now I&#8217;m in someone else&#8217;s kitchen, with someone else&#8217;s pantry and we&#8217;ve got guests for dinner. Oh dear. A quick (read &#8216;frantic&#8217;) rummage through lil&#8217; sis&#8217;&nbsp;supplies and ideas are starting to form. This is what I came up with and it was good enough to warrant photos and a recipe request from lil&#8217; sis.</p>
<p>The circumstances surrounding this meal did not lend themselves to highly specific ingredient requirements;&nbsp;i.e. go ahead and vary it up depending on what&#8217;s on hand and your own tastes.</p>
<p><span>If using store-bought pesto be sure to&nbsp;check the ingredients&nbsp;list for allergens or intolerances, and f</span>or vegan/nut-free versions skip the fetta/walnuts respectively too.</p>
<p>Serves 5</p>
<ul>
<li>1½ cups brown rice</li>
<li>1 small sweet potato</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic</li>
<li>250g swiss brown mushrooms</li>
<li>1 bunch asparagus</li>
<li>250g cherry tomatoes</li>
<li>1 tin borlotti beans, rinsed and drained (or&nbsp;<span style="font-size:14px">½ cup dried borlotti beans, soaked overnight, cooked and drained)</span></li>
<li><span>½ cup fresh basil, roughly chopped</span></li>
<li>salt and pepper</li>
<li>200g sundried tomato pesto</li>
<li>5 cups baby spinach</li>
<li>125g fetta</li>
<li>⅔ cup walnuts, lightly toasted and coarsely chopped</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180ºC (350 F). Line a baking tray with baking paper.</p>
<p><span>Place the rice in a medium saucepan along with</span><span>&nbsp;2</span><span>½ cups water. Bring to the boil over a high heat then reduce heat and simmer until rice is tender and water absorbed, about 30 minutes. (If saucepan dries out before the rice is cooked add a little more water.)</span></p>
<p><span>Meanwhile, peel the sweet potato and cut into cubes (approximately 1</span><span style="font-size:14px">½ cm or&nbsp;½ inch in size). Toss with 1 tablespoon olive oil then spread evenly on the&nbsp;baking tray. Bake in preheated oven until slightly golden and soft in the middle, about 30 minutes,&nbsp;turning after 15 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:14px">Now for the mushrooms and asparagus.&nbsp;Slice the mushrooms about&nbsp;½ cm (¼ inch) thick;&nbsp;finely dice or crush the garlic; c</span><span style="font-size:14px">ut any tough ends off the asparagus and cut into bite-sized pieces.&nbsp;Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a frying pan over&nbsp;medium heat and add the garlic. Cook for 1-2 minutes until garlic is fragrant then add the mushrooms. Cook, stirring occasionally until mushrooms just start to brown lightly. Add the asparagus and cook for a few more minutes until asparagus is heated through and mushrooms are golden.</span></p>
<p>Set the mushrooms aside heat another tablespoon of olive oil in a frying pan. Add the cherry tomatoes and cook over a medium-high heat, stirring frequently, for 10 minutes to cook the tomatoes. Use a spatula to lightly crush the tomatoes in the pan,&nbsp;just enough to split the skins and release some juice. Add the borlotti beans, basil and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Cook for another 5 minutes to heat through and thicken up some of the tomato juices.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s most of the preparation done. To put it all together transfer the rice to a large bowl and&nbsp;stir through the pesto. Add the sweet potato, the mushroom&nbsp;and asparagus mix and the tomatoes and borlotti beans and mix it all together.</p>
<p>To serve, divide baby spinach between bowls and spoon rice mixture over the top. Top with toasted walnuts and crumbled fetta. Happy dinner!</p>
<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buckwheat and chickpea tabouli</title>
		<link>/2013/04/04/2013-4-3-buckwheat-and-chickpea-tabouli/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 12:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/04/2013-4-3-buckwheat-and-chickpea-tabouli/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite my best intentions, as usual I ate too much chocolate in too short a time over Easter. As a result, part of me is craving more chocolate and other junk, a craving I'm trying very hard to ignore. At the same time, when I've had too much sugar part of me also craves really fresh and ultra-healthy food, so I made up a big bowl of this buckwheat and chickpea tabouli for dinner last night. This isn't just a salad for post-Easter detoxes though, it's tasty, nutritious and refreshing and makes a great lunch or light dinner any time.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/buckwheattaboulieditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Despite my best intentions, as usual I ate too much chocolate in too short a time over Easter. As a result, part of me is craving more chocolate and other junk, a craving I&#8217;m trying very hard to ignore. At the same time, when I&#8217;ve had too much sugar part of me also craves really fresh and ultra-healthy food, so I made up a big bowl of this buckwheat and chickpea tabouli for dinner last night. This isn&#8217;t just a salad for post-Easter detoxes though, it&#8217;s tasty, nutritious and refreshing and makes a great lunch or light dinner any time.</p>
<p>The recipe is a modification of one of Carol Fenster&#8217;s from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Gluten-Free-Vegetarian-Kitchen-Nutritious/dp/1557885109%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1557885109" target="_blank">The Gluten-Free Vegetarian Kitchen</a>. For a quicker option, or a vegan alternative, skip the egg and go straight to cooking the buckwheat in vegetable stock. Cooking the buckwheat with egg helps keep the grains separate so they don&#8217;t become mushy as cooked, so I like to do this when adding the buckwheat to salads.</p>
<p>Serves 5</p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup buckwheat</li>
<li>1 egg, lightly whisked (optional)</li>
<li>1 tablespoon canola oil (only if using the egg)</li>
<li>1 1/2 cups vegetable stock (possibly a little more of&nbsp;omitting&nbsp;the egg)</li>
<li>1/2 cup dried chickpeas, soaked, cooked and drained, or 1 400g tin chickpeas, rinsed and drained</li>
<li>4 shallots/scallions, finely sliced</li>
<li>4 tomatoes, chopped, or a punnet of cherry tomatoes, halved</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons red wine vinegar</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons lemon juice (juice of about half a lemon)</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>3 cups lettuce leaves, coarsely chopped, or mixed greens</li>
</ul>
<p>To cook buckwheat using an egg: Heat the canola oil in a saucepan over a medium heat, and swirl so the oil coats the bottom of the saucepan. In a small bowl combine the buckwheat and egg, then transfer to saucepan. Cook, stirring frequently with a fork, until egg has dried and grains are separate, 5-10 minutes. Add a scant 1 1/2 cups vegetable stock, bring to the boil, and simmer until stock is absorbed and buckwheat tender, about 20 minutes. If liquid dries up before the buckwheat is cooked, add a little extra stock or hot water.</p>
<p>Alternatively, cook buckwheat without the egg: Add 1 1/2 cups stock and buckwheat to a saucepan over medium heat. Bring stock to the boil and simmer until stock is absorbed and buckwheat tender, about 25 minutes. &nbsp;If liquid dries up before the buckwheat is cooked, add a little extra stock or hot water.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, combine chickpeas, shallots, tomatoes, parsley and mint and a large bowl. Toss with a few pinches each of salt and pepper.</p>
<p>Combine vinegar, lemon juice and olive oil in a jar and shake well to emulsify.</p>
<p>When buckwheat is cooked, allow to cool slightly (unless you&#8217;re in a hurry), before adding to the bowl with the chickpeas and tomatoes. Toss to combine. The tomatoes and herbs will stay fresher if the buckwheat isn&#8217;t really hot when it&#8217;s added. Salad can be prepared up to here in advance.</p>
<p>Just before serving, pour dressing over the tabouli and mix through. Serve spooned over lettuce.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chickpea tagine with Moroccan quinoa pilaf</title>
		<link>/2013/04/01/2013-3-30-chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/01/2013-3-30-chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This dish was inspired by a&#160;<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/fishtagine_72361">fish tagine</a>&#160;I tried a few months ago. I was really taken by the combination of flavours: it's quite sweet from the dried fruit, heavy with spices and brightened by the lemon. I didn't think the 'fishiness' worked in it though, so I turned it into a chickpea tagine with much better results. It is paired here with a simple Moroccan quinoa pilaf.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/chickpeatagineeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This dish was inspired by a <a data-cke-saved-href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/fishtagine_72361" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/fishtagine_72361" target="_blank">fish tagine</a> I tried a few months ago. I was really taken by the combination of flavours: it&#8217;s quite sweet from the dried fruit, heavy with spices and brightened by the lemon. I didn&#8217;t think the &#8216;fishiness&#8217; worked in it though, so I turned it into a chickpea tagine with much better results.</p>
<p>The tagine is paired here with a simple <a data-cke-saved-href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf#morrocanquinoapilaf" href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/3/30/chickpea-tagine-with-morrocan-quinoa-pilaf#morrocanquinoapilaf">Moroccan quinoa pilaf (recipe below)</a>, but you could also serve with cous cous (if you can have gluten), rice or a flat bread instead.</p>
<p>The tagine keeps well in the fridge; I made a large batch of it last weekend and ate it for lunch for several days thereafter.</p>
<p><a name="chickpeatagine"></a></p>
<h3 id="yui_3_17_2_1_1405597876029_15036">Chickpea tagine</h3>
<p>Serves 8</p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup dried chickpeas, soaked, cooked and drained (or 2 400g tins of chickpeas, rinsed and drained)</li>
<li>spices (see below)</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>3 medium sized onions, about 1/2 kg, grated (if you have a food processor with grater attachment this is the perfect job for it, if not you may prefer to just finely chop the onions instead &#8211; grating onions by hand is not fun)</li>
<li>1 bulb garlic, cloves separated, peeled and finely chopped or crushed</li>
<li>1 kg tomatoes, peeled, seeded and chopped* (or 800g tinned chopped tomatoes)</li>
<li>175g turkish dried apricots, halved</li>
<li>85g (1/2 cup) flaked almonds, lightly toasted&nbsp;</li>
<li>50g (1/3 cup) sultanas</li>
<li>1 teaspoon saffron stems</li>
<li>2 cups (500ml) tomato juice</li>
<li>1 cup vegetable stock</li>
<li>1 tablespoon honey (or agave nectar or sugar for a vegan alternative)</li>
<li>rind of 1 lemon, finely chopped</li>
<li>1/3 cup fresh coriander leaves, finely chopped</li>
<li>8 large lettuce leaves (or about 4 large handfuls mixed greens)</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p>*The Former Chef blog provides a good set of instructions on&nbsp;<a data-cke-saved-href="http://www.formerchef.com/2009/08/20/how-to-peel-and-seed-fresh-tomatoes/" href="http://www.formerchef.com/2009/08/20/how-to-peel-and-seed-fresh-tomatoes/">How to Peel and Seed Tomatoes</a>.</p>
<p>Spices**:</p>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons ras el hanout</li>
<li>1 tablespoon paprika</li>
<li>2 teaspoons ground tumeric</li>
<li>2 teaspoons ground coriander seed</li>
<li>2 teaspoons ground cumin</li>
<li>2 teaspoons ground cinnamon</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground nutmeg</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon ground pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>**My spice rack is fairly well stocked. Don&#8217;t feel like you have to go out and spend a small fortune on different spices though, just to make this dish &#8211; you can always make it with a smaller selection. The ras el hanout I&#8217;ve been using is one my sister bought in Morroco, and despite careful rationing I&#8217;m going to have to omit that soon, unless I can source some locally (perhaps online?). As a suggestion for simplifying the spice mix, maybe try paprika, choose one or two of coriander, cumin and tumeric, and add some cinnamon or nutmeg for warmth. With the exception of some occasional ginger bread, I despise ginger, and I also dislike hot/spicy food, but if that&#8217;s not you then ground ginger and cayenne pepper are the sorts of spices which would also work well in this dish.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Preheat oven to 170˚C (340F). Combine all spices in a small bowl. Add half the spices to the cooked chickpeas and set aside.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Place the dried apricots in a small bowl and add enough hot water to barely cover them. Place the saffron in another small bowl or cup and add 1/4 cup cold water.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat (if and ONLY IF you have a CAST IRON casserole dish, use this instead of the frying pan. If your casserole dish is ceramic, you will need it later but DO NOT put it on the stove. Yes, possibly an excessive use of caps lock here, but I learned this the hard way.)</p>
<p>Add onion to the frying pan and sauté until soft, but not brown. Add the garlic and spices and cook for another minute or two. Add the chickpeas, tomatoes, dried apricots and their soaking water, flaked almonds, sultanas, saffron in its soaking water, tomato juice, vegetable stock and honey.</p>
<p>Bring to the boil, then transfer to a casserole dish (unless you were already using a cast iron dish). Bake for one hour.</p>
<p>Fry lemon rind in 1 tablespoon olive oil for a few minutes, stopping cooking if the rind starts to brown.</p>
<p>Serve the tagine atop a lettuce leaf, and sprinkle with the cooked lemon rind and chopped coriander to garnish.</p>
<p><a name="morrocanquinoapilaf"></a></p>
<h3>Moroccan&nbsp;quinoa pilaf</h3>
<p>Serves 6-8 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 tablespoon canola oil</li>
<li>1 1/2 cups quinoa</li>
<li>1/2 cup dried fruit, chopped (I used dates and currants recently; dried apricots also work well but I omit when serving with the chickpea tagine as the tagine already has a lot of apricots in it. If using currants, sultanas, raisins or cranberries, keep these separate from the rest of the fruit.)</li>
<li>1/2 cup nuts, coarsely chopped and toasted (I like a mix of almonds, pine nuts and pistachios, but you could also try macadamias, walnuts, cashews, pecans, hazelnuts or any of your other favourite nuts.)</li>
<li>3 teaspoons spices: a similar mix to that used in the tagine. I typically add a sprinkling of each, using a bit less nutmeg and pepper than everything else.</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat the canola oil in a saucepan over medium heat, then add quinoa and toast for a few minutes. Stir through the spices.</p>
<p>Remove saucepan from the heat for a few minutes so that it cools slightly. Add 2 1/2 cups water and return to the stove. If you add the water without letting the saucepan cool first I find the water and quinoa splatter everywhere, making quite the mess and losing some of your quinoa to the stove/wall/floor/your top or hair. If using currants, sultanas, raisins or cranberries, add these now. Reserve the rest of the dried fruit for later.</p>
<p>Return saucepan to the stove. Bring to the boil then reduce heat to medium-low and simmer until water is absorbed and quinoa tender, 15-20 minutes. Add a little more water during cooking if needed. You can tell the quinoa is cooked because the little rings around the outside of the seed will start to separate from the central part.</p>
<p>Stir through remaining dried fruit. Pilaf can be prepared up to here in advance. Sprinkle with nuts just before serving, so that the nuts remain nice and crunchy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mixed bean and avocado salad</title>
		<link>/2013/03/08/2013-3-3-mixed-bean-and-avocado-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 10:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/03/08/2013-3-3-mixed-bean-and-avocado-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Sitting down to write my first post it seems natural to start with my all time favourite recipe to share with people. How did this recipe earn its status? Well, it's one of our favourites to eat because it's super tasty and packed full of nutrients, and at the same time is really quick and easy to prepare.</p><div><span style="color: rgb(51, 51, 51); font-size: 14px; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: 24px; "><br></span></div>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Mixedbean26avocadosaladresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Sitting down to write my first post and a natural starting point is my all time favourite recipe to share with people. How did this recipe earn its status? Well, it&#8217;s one of our favourites to eat because it&#8217;s super tasty and packed full of nutrients, and at the same time is really quick and easy to prepare.</p>
<p>Serves 4-5</p>
<ul>
<li>1/2 cup walnuts, roasted and coarsely chopped</li>
<li>800g tin mixed beans,&nbsp;rinsed and drained (I like the Edgell Four Bean Mix. An alternative to tinned beans is to use about 1 cup dry beans, soaked overnight, boiled and drained).</li>
<li>1/2 red onion, finely diced</li>
<li>2 avocados, cut into 1/2 inch cubes</li>
<li>80 grams fetta</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons balsamic vinegar</li>
<li>3 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>a few pinches each salt &amp; pepper</li>
<li>a few sprigs basil &amp;/or oregano, finely chopped (optional)</li>
<li>4 cups baby spinach</li>
</ul>
<p>In a bowl, combine beans, onion, balsamic vinegar, olive oil, salt, pepper and herbs if using. Adjust the balsamic, olive oil and seasoning to taste. Add the avocado. Salad can be prepared to here in advance and refrigerated (the avocado will keep as long as it&#8217;s well coated with the vinaigrette). To serve, distribute the baby spinach between serving bowls and spoon the bean and avocado mix over the top. Sprinkle with walnuts and crumble fetta over the top. I generally have this with a glass of juice, or follow with a piece of fruit, as the extra vitamin C helps with absorption of the iron from the spinach and beans. Enjoy!</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
