<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hors d&#8217;oeuvres &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/hors-doeuvres/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 06:51:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ricotta-stuffed mushrooms</title>
		<link>/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 03:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hors d'oeuvres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/01/12/2013-12-15-ricotta-stuffed-mushrooms/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span>If you're in Australia at the moment, chances are you've got a barbecue or three coming up. If you're in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Ricottastuffedmushroomseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re in Australia at the moment, chances are you&#8217;ve got a barbecue or three coming up. If you&#8217;re in cooler climes, then you might be looking for cosy dishes to bake. Either way, these stuffed mushrooms fit the bill; talk about versatile!</p>
<p>Lately I&#8217;ve been using largish button mushrooms in this recipe, as they&#8217;re the perfect size for sharing.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re after meal-sized servings though, try using portobello mushrooms instead.</p>
<p>These mushrooms can be baked, grilled or barbecued &#8211; the preparation is all the same.</p>
<p>For a super-quick variant, just mix the ricotta and sun-dried tomatoes with salt and pepper to taste, perhaps add some dry herbs if they&#8217;re handy, pile on top of portobello mushrooms and add to the barbie.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts.</p>
<p>Makes 12 pieces</p>
<p>12 medium-large button mushrooms (or 3-4 portobello mushrooms)</p>
<p>2 cloves garlic, finely chopped</p>
<p>1 tablespoon olive oil</p>
<p>300g ricotta</p>
<p>1/4 cup sun-dried tomatoes, drained and chopped</p>
<p>2 tablespoons pine nuts, toasted</p>
<p>2 tablespoons fresh oregano and/or thyme leaves, finely chopped</p>
<p>salt and pepper</p>
<p>If baking, preheat oven to 180˚C (350F).</p>
<p>Remove stems from the mushrooms and coarsely chop, discarding any woody bits. To remove the stem of a mushroom: hold the mushroom in one hand and use your other hand to pinch the stem, squeezing so the stem splits. Pinch the two halves of the stem together and squeeze so it&#8217;s now split into four pieces. Now twist the stem, and it should come easily away from the mushroom.</p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a small skillet over medium heat. Add mushroom stems and garlic and sauté until garlic is fragrant and stems are lightly browned.</p>
<p>Wrap ricotta in paper towels or cheese cloth and squeeze to remove excess liquid.</p>
<p>Combine mushroom stems, ricotta, sun-dried tomatoes, pine nuts and fresh herbs in a bowl and mix to combine. Season with a few pinches of salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>If using portobello mushrooms, sprinkle the underside of the mushrooms lightly with salt and pepper. Skip this step if using button mushrooms (I think it&#8217;s too fiddly and you&#8217;ve already seasoned the stuffing).</p>
<p>Place mushrooms on a baking tray, skin-side facing down, and fill with the ricotta stuffing. Your mushrooms are now ready to cook, but cooking time will depend on the size of your mushrooms and method of cooking. Small mushrooms will cook in 10 minutes under a grill, portobello mushrooms may take 30-40 mins to bake. As a guide, check button mushrooms after 10-15 minutes, and portobello mushrooms after 20-30 minutes. The mushrooms will be ready when the ricotta is golden-brown and the mushroom is heated through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Name this dish!</title>
		<link>/2013/04/01/2013-3-30-name-this-dish/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 18:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hors d'oeuvres]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/01/2013-3-30-name-this-dish/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Figs are in season and abundant at the Farmers' Market; as I adore fresh figs I find this very exciting. Having bought two bags of figs at the markets last weekend, I recalled fondly some very tasty fig and brie mini pizzas I made for a dinner party a few years ago. I wanted a healthier option to the pizza base though, so paired the toppings with some linseed meal crackers. The only thing is, I need your help to name them. The best I can come up with is 'Toasted fig, brie, balsamic caramelised&#160;onion and walnut linseed slices' which, while descriptive, is a little long. So, have a go at making these and suggest a new name in the comments section.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/toastedfigbrielinseedsliceseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Figs are in season and abundant at the Farmers&#8217; Market; as I adore fresh figs I find this very exciting. Having bought two bags of figs at the markets last weekend, I recalled fondly some very tasty fig and brie mini pizzas I made for a dinner party a few years ago. I wanted a healthier option to the pizza base though, so paired the toppings with some linseed meal crackers. The only thing is, I need your help to name them. The best I can come up with is &#8216;Toasted fig, brie, balsamic caramelised&nbsp;onion and walnut linseed slices&#8217; which, while descriptive, is a little long. So, have a go at making these and suggest a new name in the comments section.</p>
<p>Makes about 20</p>
<p>Linseed crackers:</p>
<ul>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>2 cups linseed meal</li>
<li>1/2 cup freshly grated parmesan cheese</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon salt</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 teaspoon fresh rosemary, finely chopped, or 1/2 teaspoon dried</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried sage</li>
</ul>
<p>Toppings:</p>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>3 red onions, sliced</li>
<li>1 tablespoon golden syrup or honey</li>
<li>2-3 tablespoons balsamic vinegar</li>
<li>10 fresh figs, quartered</li>
<li>100g brie, cut into 20 wedges</li>
<li>1/2 cup walnuts, broken into pieces or coarsely chopped</li>
</ul>
<p>Make the linseed crackers:</p>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F), and lightly oil one large or two smaller baking tray(s). Combine all ingredients in a large mixing bowl. Stir in 1 cup water. Spread mix over the tray(s) and top with a sheet of baking paper. Use a rolling pin to roll out the mixture until it is about 5mm thick. Press in the edges so they are not too much thinner than the middle or else they&#8217;ll burn before the rest firms up. Remove the paper and bake in the oven until crackers are firm on the surface (they&#8217;ll still be a bit soft in the middle, but will harden as they cool), and starting to brown around the edges, 15-20 minutes.</p>
<p>Score into squares and use a spatula to remove crackers to a cooling rack.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, caramelise the onions:</p>
<p>Heat the olive oil in a skillet over medium heat and add the onions. Cook until the onions soften and begin to brown, about 10 minutes. Reduce heat to low and stir in the vinegar and golden syrup or honey. Cook until onions are very soft and liquid has thickened, maybe another 15-20 minutes. Taste and adjust with a little extra vinegar or sweetener as needed.</p>
<p>To complete:</p>
<p>Return linseed crackers to the baking tray. Top each cracker with a heaped tablespoon of caramelised onion, two fig quarters, a slice of brie and finally a teaspoon of walnut pieces. Bake at 180˚C until brie has melted and walnuts are lightly browned, about 10 minutes. Enjoy immediately.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
