<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fish &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/fish/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 06:34:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Grilled salmon with orange-soy sauce and fennel puree</title>
		<link>/2013/04/27/2013-4-22-grilled-salmon-with-orange-soy-sauce-and-fennel-puree/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 04:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/27/2013-4-22-grilled-salmon-with-orange-soy-sauce-and-fennel-puree/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This orange-soy sauce, out of&#160;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fish-Without-Doubt-Essential-Companion/dp/061853119X%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D061853119X">Fish Without A Doubt</a>, is one of my favorites. The combination of the sweet, salty and buttery is just devine. The fennel puree is more mellow and adds a nice contrast.&#160;Try pairing this with the&#160;<a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/22/marinated-mushroom-fennel-and-grilled-potato-salad">marinated mushrooms, fennel and grilled potato salad</a>.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/salmonorangesoyfennel.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p><span style="line-height: 24px;">This orange-soy sauce, out of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fish-Without-Doubt-Essential-Companion/dp/061853119X%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D061853119X" target="_blank">Fish Without A Doubt</a>, is one of my favorites. The combination of the sweet, salty and buttery is just devine. The fennel puree is more mellow and adds a nice contrast.&nbsp;Try pairing this with the&nbsp;</span><a href="/2013/04/25/2013-4-22-marinated-mushroom-fennel-and-grilled-potato-salad/" target="_blank" style="line-height: 24px;">marinated mushrooms, fennel and grilled potato salad</a><span style="line-height: 24px;">.</span></p>
<p>The orange-soy sauce is very rich; it finishes off a fillet of salmon nicely, but if serving with a white fish I&#8217;d suggest using sparingly.</p>
<p>I like peanut oil for grilling as it has a high smoke point so stands up to the high temperatures of grilling better than, say, olive oil. For a nut-free version, substitute another oil with a relatively high smoke point, such as canola oil.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>300-350g salmon fillets</li>
<li>Peanut oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li><a href="#fennelpuree">Fennel puree (recipe below)</a></li>
<li><a href="#orangesoysauce">Orange-soy sauce (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Rinse salmon fillets and pat dry. The salmon I buy at the markets is often thick at one end and much thinner at the other. If this is the case for your fish, cut into &#8216;thick&#8217; and &#8216;thin&#8217; pieces. I&#8217;m not sure how conventional this is, but I find separating the fillets like this allows you to cook both parts nicely, without leaving the thick section underdone or the thin part dry.</p>
<p>Brush salmon with a little peanut oil to coat, and place, skin side up, on a tray. Sprinkle lightly with salt and pepper. Cook fillets under grill or broiler for about 8 minutes, for inch thick fillets. If you have thinner parts as well, add these after about 3 minutes and they should be done at about the same time as the rest. You can check the salmon is cooked by cutting into one of the fillets, but I usually aim for salmon to be very slightly undercooked when I take it out. The salmon will continue to cook from the residual heat as you plate it up, and salmon dries out very quickly with only a couple of extra minutes of cooking.</p>
<p>Dollop fennel puree onto plates and place salmon next to or atop the puree. Spoon orange-soy sauce over and around the salmon and serve immediately.</p>
<h3 id="fennelpuree">Fennel puree</h3>
<p>Serves 2-3 as a side. Note you&#8217;ll also need a little cheese cloth and twine (or similar). If you don&#8217;t have these, try using a tea ball instead.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large bulb fennel, trimmed and cut into 1cm thick slices</li>
<li>2 tablespoons unsalted butter</li>
<li>1 teaspoon fennel seeds, toasted</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon dried tarragon</li>
<li>1/3 cup dry white wine (optional)</li>
</ul>
<p>Wrap the fennel seeds and tarragon in cheese cloth and tie closed to form a little bundle.</p>
<p>Melt butter in a frying pan over medium heat and add the fennel slices. Cook for about 5 minutes until fennel starts to soften. Add the bundle containing the fennel seeds and tarragon. If using wine, add this now and cook until the pan is almost dry.</p>
<p>Add enough hot water to barely cover the fennel. Cover the frying pan with a lid if it has one, otherwise cover firmly with a sheet of alfoil. If using a lid, leave slightly ajar to allow steam to escape (unless it has a small hole in it for this purpose). If using foil, prick a couple of small holes in it with a fork or skewer. Cook until fennel is very soft and pan is almost dry, 15-20 minutes. Add extra hot water while cooking if needed.</p>
<p>Remove bundle and puree fennel in a food processor. Serve warm.</p>
</p>
<h3 id="orangesoysauce">Orange-soy sauce</h3>
<p>For the quantitiy of sauce below I do it all in one saucepan. If making a larger batch I&#8217;d suggest starting with a larger pan to speed up the reduction of the juice, then transferring the reduction to a small saucepan to finish off the cooking.</p>
<p>Makes about 1/3 cup, enough to accompany 2-3 serves of salmon or more of a more delicate fish.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup fresh orange juice (juice of 2-3 oranges)</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon soy sauce (if you can&#8217;t find gluten-free soy sauce, use tamari instead)</li>
<li>30g (2 tablespoons) unsalted butter, chopped into pieces</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat orange juice in a small saucepan and bring to the boil (keep an eye on it as the juice will boil over if it gets too hot). Reduce heat so you have an active simmer and cook until juice is reduced to 2-3 tablespoons, by which point it should be starting to thicken. Stir in the soy sauce. Add the butter one or two pieces at a time, whisking to incorporate before adding more, until all the butter is added and sauce is well mixed. If not serving immediately, then just before serving reheat and whisk to recombine if the sauce has started to separate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grilled swordfish with hoisin glaze and green curry coconut sauce</title>
		<link>/2013/04/12/2013-4-11-grilled-swordfish-with-hoisin-glaze-and-green-curry-coconut-sauce/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 11:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/12/2013-4-11-grilled-swordfish-with-hoisin-glaze-and-green-curry-coconut-sauce/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The weekend is just around the corner, and on weekends I usually cook fish. ​I like to cook fish the same day I buy it, and I can get beautiful fresh fish from the markets on Saturdays. This swordfish, paired with coconut rice and steamed bok choy, is last weekend's creation. Swordfish has a firmer, more dense consistency than most other fish, which isn't overwhelmed by the strong flavours of the glaze and sauce here. I've also made this with salmon which was very successful too (cooking time just needs to be increased a tad).</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/grilledswordfisheditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>The weekend is just around the corner, and on weekends I usually cook fish. I like to cook fish the same day I buy it, and I can get beautiful fresh fish from the markets on Saturdays. This swordfish, paired with coconut rice and steamed bok choy, is last weekend&#8217;s creation. Swordfish has a firmer, more dense consistency than most other fish, which isn&#8217;t overwhelmed by the strong flavours of the glaze and sauce here. I&#8217;ve also made this with salmon which was very successful too (cooking time just needs to be increased a tad).</p>
<p>The glaze and sauce are based on recipes in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Fish-Without-Doubt-Essential-Companion/dp/061853119X%3FSubscriptionId%3D0ENGV10E9K9QDNSJ5C82%26tag%3Dfredel09-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D061853119X" target="_blank">Fish Without A Doubt</a> by Rick Moonen and Roy Finamore. I prefer to keep my cooking quite mild, but if you&#8217;re okay with spicy food you may like to increase the quantity of curry paste used. I really like coconut so use lots of coconut milk with the rice, but it does make it a little &#8216;gluggier&#8217;. If you&#8217;d rather a consistency more like steamed rice just replace a portion of the coconut milk with water.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, simply substitute the peanut oil for vegetable or canola (and check the ingredients of the green curry paste you buy).</p>
<p>Serves 4</p>
<ul>
<li>600-700g swordfish steaks</li>
<li>Peanut oil&nbsp;<span style="letter-spacing: normal;">&nbsp;</span>(or substitute vegetable or canola oil)</li>
<li><a href="#hoisinglaze">Hoisin glaze (recipe below)</a></li>
<li><a href="#greencurrycoconutsauce">Green curry coconut sauce (recipe below)</a></li>
<li><a href="#coconutrice">Coconut rice (recipe below)</a></li>
<li>2 bunches bok choy, leaves separated and washed</li>
<li>1 tablespoon desiccated or shredded coconut, lightly toasted</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh coriander, finely chopped</li>
</ul>
<p>Start by preparing the rice, glaze and sauce as below; once they&#8217;re done the bok choy and fish wont take long.</p>
<p>Steam the bok choy: This is perhaps a bit unconventional, but I cut the thick stems from the leaves and put the stems in the steamer first. After 2 minutes, I add the leaves and steam for another minute.</p>
<p>Brush swordfish with oil and season with salt and pepper. Heat a grill pan (if you don&#8217;t have a grill pan, a frying pan will also work) over medium-high heat. Grill swordfish for 5 minutes. Brush the top side with glaze then flip and grill for about 1 minute, until barely cooked through. Brush the (now) top side with glaze.</p>
<p>To serve: Divide bok choy among four plates, spoon coconut rice over the top and sprinkle with coconut and coriander. Pour green curry coconut sauce over the rice and around the plate. Finally, top with the swordfish, and if you haven&#8217;t used all the glaze add this to the fish now.</p>
<h3 id="hoisinglaze">Hoisin Glaze</h3>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons hoisin sauce</li>
<li>1 tablespoon lime juice (juice of about half a lime)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey</li>
<li>1 clove garlic, very finely chopped or minced</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh coriander, finely chopped</li>
<li>pinch salt</li>
<li>pinch pepper</li>
</ul>
<p>Simply combine all ingredients in a small bowl and mix well. This will keep for a couple of days in the fridge.</p>
<h3 id="greencurrycoconutsauce">Green Curry Coconut Sauce</h3>
<ul>
<li>2 tablespoons peanut oil (or substitute vegetable or canola oil)</li>
<li>1 stick lemongrass, finely chopped</li>
<li>4 cloves garlic, finely chopped or minced</li>
<li>2 kaffir lime leaves</li>
<li>2 teaspoons green curry paste</li>
<li>1/4 cup dry white wine (optional)</li>
<li>400mL coconut milk</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>1 teaspoon sugar</li>
<li>2 teaspoons lime juice</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat oil in a small saucepan over medium-high heat. Add the lemongrass and garlic and cook, stirring, until fragrant, a few minutes. Add the kaffir lime leaves and curry paste and cook for another minute. Add the wine (if using, otherwise go straight to adding the coconut milk), stir to dissolve curry paste, and bring to a boil. Reduce heat slightly and simmer until the wine has reduced by about half and you have a thicker consistency, about 10 minutes.</p>
<p>Stir in the coconut milk and season with a pinch of salt. Bring to the boil, but keep an eye on it as it can boil over quickly. Reduce heat to low and simmer until thick enough to coat the back of a spoon, 20-30 minutes.</p>
<p>Strain the sauce through a fine mesh&nbsp;sieve to remove the solids, pushing down with the back of a spoon to squeeze out the liquid. Add the sugar and lime juice and season with a little extra salt to taste.</p>
<p>Sauce will keep for a couple of days in the fridge, but warm it before serving.</p>
<h3 id="coconutrice">Coconut Rice</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 cup white rice</li>
<li>400mL coconut milk</li>
</ul>
<p>Rinse the rice to remove excess starch. You can do this by placing rice in a bowl or saucepan and adding cold water to cover the rice by a couple of inches. Swirl rice with your hands and strain. Repeat until the water remains almost clear when swirled, maybe 4-6 times.</p>
<p>Combine the coconut milk and rice in a saucepan over medium heat and bring to the boil. Reduce heat to low and simmer gently, stirring&nbsp;occasionally (the coconut milk will stick to the bottom of the pan more readily than rice cooked in water). Cook until coconut milk is absorbed and rice tender, about 15-20 minutes. Add a little extra water as needed during cooking; I generally add a total of 1/4-1/2 cup extra.</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
