<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorised &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/uncategorised/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 06:34:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Fruit and nut energy balls</title>
		<link>/2013/12/01/2013-11-25-fruit-and-nut-energy-balls/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 07:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet treats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/12/01/2013-11-25-fruit-and-nut-energy-balls/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so to say this blog's been neglected lately is something of an understatement. Sometimes life just gets in the way and there are only so many things you can keep up with at once. Well, life has settled down somewhat lately, and I've been getting a number of requests to start posting again, so here goes...</p><p>I've also been getting several enquiries around the gym about some of the concoctions I'm seen snacking on so I'll start by sharing some of those. I eat these fruit and nut balls as a high energy-density 'fast' food to keep me going during long training sessions. If I'm doing two classes back-to-back I generally need to eat in between or my blood sugar can drop too low, but I don't have much time and need something light enough that I can keep working on straight away.</p><p>For a seasonal touch: these would also be a nice treat as part of a Christmas spread.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Fruitandnutballseditedcompressed.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Okay, so to say this blog&#8217;s been neglected lately is something of an understatement. Sometimes life just gets in the way and there are only so many things you can keep up with at once. Well, life has settled down somewhat lately, and I&#8217;ve been getting a number of requests to start posting again, so here goes&#8230;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also been getting several enquiries around the gym about some of the concoctions I&#8217;m seen snacking on so I&#8217;ll start by sharing some of those. I eat these fruit and nut balls as a high energy-density &#8216;fast&#8217; food to keep me going during long training sessions. If I&#8217;m doing two classes back-to-back I generally need to eat in between or my blood sugar can drop too low, but I don&#8217;t have much time and need something light enough that I can keep working on straight away.</p>
<p><span>The ingredients are quite flexible, as long as the ratios of fruit and nuts are kept similar. I use dried dates (because they&#8217;re both very tasty and very cheap) and prunes (because they&#8217;re sticky and help hold everything together) as the base. Go ahead and experiment with whatever fruits and nuts you prefer, but I&#8217;d recommend keeping the prunes in as they&#8217;re a good culinary &#8216;glue&#8217;. Also don&#8217;t go overboard with the seeds, I find they don&#8217;t crush up and hold together as well as the nuts.&nbsp;The ingredients below are suggestions, I&#8217;ll typically choose just a few based on what&#8217;s in my pantry.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;I make up a big batch of balls and keep them in the fridge, taking about 3 balls as a &#8216;serving&#8217;. I can attest to them lasting at least 3-4 weeks in the fridge, mine have never lasted longer as they&#8217;re all gone by then!</p>
<p>For a seasonal touch: these would also be a nice treat as part of a Christmas spread.</p>
<p><span>Makes approximately 3 dozen balls</span></p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup dried pitted dates</li>
<li>1 cup pitted prunes</li>
<li>1 cup mixed dried fruit (I like sultanas, cranberries, apricots, goji berries but feel free to try anything else)</li>
<li>2 cups mixed nuts and seeds (I like walnuts, cashews, blanched almonds, macadamias, hazelnuts, pepitas&#8230; the list goes on&#8230; but once again try whatever you like)</li>
<li>2/3 cup desiccated coconut</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine all ingredients except coconut in a food processor and process until fruit and nuts are well chopped and mixture holds together well. If, like me, you&#8217;ve just dumped in all the fruit then all the nuts, or vice versa, you may need to stop the processor and stir the mixture up a bit to get it well combined then process a little longer. Or you could do the sensible thing and toss the fruit and nuts together first then process.</p>
<p><span>Put the coconut in a cereal bowl. Scoop out about a tablespoon of the fruit and nut mixture (enough to make a roughly 1 inch diameter ball). Roll into a ball between your hands then roll in the coconut to coat. Set aside and repeat until all the mixture has been used up. Try not to eat all at once and enjoy!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buckwheat porridge</title>
		<link>/2013/06/23/2013-6-23-buckwheat-porridge/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 10:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/06/23/2013-6-23-buckwheat-porridge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Winter has well and truly settled upon Canberra, and winter means cold mornings and warm breakfasts. The medical advice in Australia is that oats are not safe for those with coeliac disease. (I know this varies in other countries.) When I was first diagnosed my gastroenterologist explained that the reason for this is two-fold: First, oats and wheat are usually grown in adjacent&#160;fields&#160;and processed on the same equipment so the risk of cross-contamination is very high. Second, oats contain a protein (called avenin) which is similar in structure to gluten and which around 1 in 5 coeliacs also react to.&#160;<a href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/coeliac-disease/faq.html">Coeliac Australia</a>&#160;explain that there is no way to test who will react to avenin in advance, and so they actually class avenin as a type of gluten and advise that coeliacs shout not eat oats. I developed this recipe the first winter after I was diagnosed with coeliac disease and it has been our regular cold-weather breakfast ever since.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/buckwheatporridgeeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Winter has well and truly settled upon Canberra, and winter means cold mornings and warm breakfasts. The medical advice in Australia is that oats are not safe for those with coeliac disease. (I know this varies in other countries.) When I was first diagnosed my gastroenterologist explained that the reason for this is two-fold: First, oats and wheat are often grown in adjacent&nbsp;fields&nbsp;and processed on the same equipment so the risk of cross-contamination is very high. Second, oats contain a protein (called avenin) which is similar in structure to gluten and which around 1 in 5 coeliacs also react to. <a href="http://www.coeliac.org.au/coeliac-disease/faq.html" target="_blank">Coeliac Australia</a> explain that there is no way to test who will react to avenin in advance, and so they actually class avenin as a type of gluten and advise that coeliacs should not eat oats. I developed this recipe the first winter after I was diagnosed with coeliac disease and it has been our regular cold-weather breakfast ever since.</p>
<p>I make up containers of the mixed fruit and toasted nuts in advance and keep these in the pantry (store the fruit and nuts separately though to help keep the nuts nice and crunchy). The porridge can be left to simmer while you go and have a shower, but I&#8217;d only recommend this if you&#8217;ve made it a few times and know your stove so it neither boils over nor burns on the bottom in the mean time.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version skip the nuts. I started using soy milk as my partner is lactose-intolerant, but if lactose is okay you could substitute dairy milk.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1/3 cup buckwheat</li>
<li>1 cup soy milk, plus extra to serve</li>
<li>1 cardamon pod, bruised</li>
<li>2 cloves</li>
<li>1-inch piece cinnamon stick (a rolling pin works well to break up a tough stick of cinnamon)&nbsp;</li>
<li>1 apple or pear, cored and cut into 1-2cm cubes</li>
<li>1 banana, thinly sliced</li>
<li>2 tablespoons mixed dried fruit (I use sultanas, cranberries, and chopped dried apricots)&nbsp;</li>
<li>2 tablespoons mixed nuts, toasted (I use slivered almonds, chopped hazelnuts and chopped walnuts)</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey, or to taste (I just dip the tip of each dessert spoon in the honey as serving and this is about right)&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine buckwheat, 1 cup milk and the spices in a small saucepan over a medium heat and bring to the boil. Reduce heat to low and simmer, stirring&nbsp;occasionally,&nbsp;until buckwheat is tender and milk absorbed, 20-30 minutes depending on how strong a simmer you have. If porridge dries out, add a little extra milk or the liquid from stewing the fruit (keep reading).</p>
<p>Meanwhile, stew the apple or pear: Place apple or pear in a small microwave-safe bowl, and pour over enough water to barely cover the fruit. Microwave for 3-5 minutes until tender then drain. (A ripe pear will cook in 3 minutes, an apple covered with cold water will need 5 minutes.)</p>
<p>Once the buckwheat is cooked, fish out the spices. Mix in banana and apple or pear and divide into two cereal bowls. Sprinkle each bowl with a spoonful each of dried fruit and nuts, stir through a little honey and add extra milk to taste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spanakopita filled chickpea crepes</title>
		<link>/2013/05/08/2013-4-30-spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 14:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/05/08/2013-4-30-spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This came about from my unwillingness to give up ​my favourite Spanakopita filling from my pre-coeliac-diagnosis days. Spanakopita is a Greek spinach and cheese pie. Here, I've taken the same spinach and cheese mix, rolled it up in chickpea crepes and topped with tomato sauce.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/spanakopitachickpeacrepeseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This came about from my unwillingness to give up my favourite Spanakopita filling from my pre-coeliac-diagnosis days. Spanakopita is a Greek spinach and cheese pie. Here, I&#8217;ve taken the same spinach and cheese mix, rolled it up in chickpea crepes and topped with tomato sauce.</p>
<p>I used to make this with buckwheat crepes and ended up making chickpea crepes this time somewhat by accident. Well almost &#8211; I didn&#8217;t misread the label on the flour I was using, but I did forget to check the supplies in my pantry before doing the shopping. It turned out to be somewhat serendipitous as&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 1.6em;">I think the chickpea flour actually results in a much better texture.</span></p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts.</p>
<p>Serves 3-4 as a main or 6 as a starter</p>
<ul>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 onion, finely diced</span></li>
<li>1 large bunch spinach or silverbeet, stems&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 1.6em;">removed and finely chopped</span></li>
<li>2 eggs, lightly whisked</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">300g ricotta</span></li>
<li>120g fetta</li>
<li>1/4 cup fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>2 tablespoons fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>a few pinches ground nutmeg</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 cup freshly grated parmesan, plus extra to serve</li>
<li>1/4 cup pine nuts, lightly toasted (be careful, they burn easily)</li>
<li><a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/30/spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes#chickpeacrepes">chickpea crepes (recipe below)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/30/spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes#tomatosauce">tomato sauce (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F). Brush a baking dish (about 20cm x 30cm) lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add onion and cook until tender, about 10 minutes. Add spinach and cook until just wilted. Transfer onion and spinach to a colander and allow to drain and cool.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, mix together eggs, cheeses, herbs and spices. Stir in the cooled spinach mixture.</p>
<p>Spread a chickpea crepe flat and spoon 3-4 tablespoons<span>&nbsp;</span><span>(about 1/6 of the total filling, depending on how many crepes you have)&nbsp;</span><span>of the mixture in a line down the middle. Sprinkle 1-2 teaspoons pine nuts over the top. Fold one side of the crepe over the filling, and roll towards the other side until you have a nice roll. Place roll in the baking dish with the &#8216;loose&#8217; side down to hold the roll closed. Repeat with remaining crepes.</span></p>
<p>Bake in the oven until filling has cooked through, about 40 minutes. If crepes are starting to brown (check after about 20 minutes), cover the dish with a sheet of alfoil, pricked in a couple of places to let steam escape.</p>
<p>Serve with tomato sauce spooned over the top and sprinkled with parmesan cheese.</p>
<p><a name="chickpeacrepes"></a></p>
<h3>Chickpea crepes</h3>
<p>For dairy/lactose-free crepes, use a non-dairy milk such as soy.</p>
<p>Makes about 6 20cm crepes</p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup chickpea flour</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">pinch salt</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 egg, lightly beaten</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">3/4 cup milk</span></li>
<li>canola oil</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine flour and salt in a mixing bowl. In a smaller bowl, whisk together egg and milk. Add the liquids to the dry ingredients and whisk well until you have a smooth batter.</p>
<p>Heat a non-stick frying pan over a medium-high heat and add about 1 tablespoon oil to coat. Add about 1/2 cup (I use one ladle-full) of batter to the pan and swirl pan so batter spreads out to form a thin layer. For the spanakopita filled chickpea crepes, you want your crepes quite thin so you can roll them up; if the mixture isn&#8217;t spreading out enough you can thin the batter by adding a little more milk. Cook until top has just set and underside is golden. This will only take a minute or two once your pan is hot. Flip and cook for another minute or so until golden on both sides. Set aside, atop some paper towel to drain any excess oil. Repeat until all batter is cooked, adding a little oil between crepes if needed.</p>
<p><a name="tomatosauce"></a></p>
<h3>Tomato sauce</h3>
<p>Makes 2-3 cups</p>
<ul>
<li>1 tablespoon olive oil</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 onion, finely diced</span></li>
<li>3 cloves garlic, finely diced or crushed</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried oregano*</li>
<li>1/4 cup red wine (optional)</li>
<li>1 kg tomatoes, peeled, seeded and chopped**</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1/2 cup fresh basil, finely diced*</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">salt</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">pepper</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;"></span><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">sugar (optional, if needed)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">*Use fresh or dried herbs, depending on what&#8217;s on hand. Just adjust the quantities (you&#8217;ll need less dried than fresh) and add dried herbs earlier on in the cooking than fresh.</span></p>
<p><span>**The Former Chef blog provides a good se</span><span>t of instructions on&nbsp;</span><a href="http://www.formerchef.com/2009/08/20/how-to-peel-and-seed-fresh-tomatoes/">How to Peel and Seed Tomatoes</a><span>.</span></p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add onion and saute until tender, about 10 minutes. Add garlic and dried herbs and cook for another minute or two until fragrant. If using wine, add this now and cook until pan is almost dry (otherwise go straight to the next step).</p>
<p>Add the tomatoes and cook until sauce has thickened. I find this can take up to about half an hour. 5-10 minutes before sauce is ready, stir in the fresh herbs. Add a few pinches each of salt and pepper, to taste. Taste the sauce and if it is tart add a little sugar &#8211; only about 1/4-1/2 teaspoon to start, then adjust as needed. If you accidentally make your sauce too sweet you can balance it out with a little lemon juice.</p>
<p>You can serve this sauce immediately, or keep it in the fridge for a few days.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roast eggplant puree</title>
		<link>/2013/05/01/2013-4-28-roast-eggplant-puree/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 11:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/05/01/2013-4-28-roast-eggplant-puree/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This isn't quite quick, due to the cooking time required, but it is dead easy to make, and oh so yummy. It's a great option as a side when you're preparing something else which is a bit involved, as this will take little effort from you and can cook in the mean time.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/eggplantpureeeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t quite quick, due to the cooking time required, but it is dead easy to make, and oh so yummy. It&#8217;s a great option as a side when you&#8217;re preparing something else which is a bit involved, as this will take little effort from you and can cook in the mean time.</p>
<p>You could also try serving this sprinkled with pine nuts and/or goat&#8217;s cheese.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large eggplant, cut in half lengthways</li>
<li>1 large red capsicum</li>
<li>1 head garlic (unpeeled)</li>
<li>1/2 cup fresh basil, finely chopped</li>
<li>2-3 tablespoons balsamic vinegar</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>2 cups baby spinach</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 200˚C (390 F).</p>
<p>Sprinkle cut sides of eggplant with salt and set aside, cut side down, to drain for at least 30 minutes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, brush garlic lightly with olive oil and place it and the capsicum on a baking tray and cook until the skin on the capsicum has blistered and the garlic is tender, about 30 minutes. Turn the capsicum during cooking so the skin blisters on all sides. Set garlic and capsicum aside until cool enough to handle.</p>
<p>Rinse eggplant well and pat dry then brush the cut sides with olive oil. Place eggplant on a baking tray, cut sides face-down. Bake until eggplant is very tender (the skin will also be slightly crinkly), about 30-40 minutes.</p>
<p>Squeeze garlic out of its peel and into a bowl. Peel and seed capsicum, pat dry and finely dice, then add to the garlic. Peel eggplant skin away from the flesh (or if it&#8217;s not coming away easily, scoop flesh out with a metal spoon). Finely dice eggplant flesh and add to the bowl. Add the fresh basil, along with the balsamic, 1 tablespoon olive oil and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Adjust the vinegar and seasoning to taste.</p>
<p>Serve warm or at room temperature, spooned over the baby spinach.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mushroom and chestnut gratin</title>
		<link>/2013/04/30/2013-4-18-mushroom-and-chestnut-gratin/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 12:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/30/2013-4-18-mushroom-and-chestnut-gratin/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​The changing seasons is always an exciting time in the culinary year, so many new foods coming into season!​ One of those I await most eagerly each autumn is chestnuts, and the first dish I make with them is this mushroom and chestnut gratin.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Mushroomchestnutgratineditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>The changing seasons is always an exciting time in the culinary year, so many new foods coming into season! One of those I await most eagerly each autumn is chestnuts, and the first dish I make with them is this mushroom and chestnut gratin.</p>
<p>I love chestnuts, but be warned they are very time consuming to peel. Don&#8217;t get too excited if you find Easy-To-Peel chestnuts as I have only ever found one place which sells Easy-To-Peel chestnuts which are in fact easy to peel (if you&#8217;re in Canberra, it&#8217;s Featherdale Chestnuts at the Capital Region Farmers Market). Good company, good music or a TV show in the background can make it more tolerable if you have particularly stubborn chestnuts. Also, don&#8217;t worry if your chestnuts break up while peeling them, you&#8217;ll be chopping them for this recipe anyway.</p>
<p>For a vegan or dairy/lactose-free version, omit the parmesan.</p>
<p>Serves 4-6</p>
<ul>
<li>500g chestnuts, peeled* and coarsely chopped</li>
<li>1 cup vegetable stock</li>
<li>1 cup fresh parsley finely chopped</li>
<li>1/4 cup pine nuts, toasted**</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>500g mushrooms, cut into quarters, halves or left whole, depending on size (you want bite-size pieces, keeping in mind they will shrink a little as they cook.)</li>
<li>salt (optional)</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>1 cup freshly grated parmesan cheese</li>
</ul>
<p>*A good set of instructions on how to peel chestnuts can be found at<a href="http://www.italianfoodforever.com/2009/11/how-to-peel-a-chestnut/" target="_blank"> Italian Food Forever</a>. There are two minor modifications I would recommend to their method: 1. I use a stanley knife to score the chestnuts; and 2. I&#8217;d suggest wearing rubber gloves on one or both hands while removing the peel, as it will come away most easily when the chestnut is straight out of the boiling water and very hot.</p>
<p>**Be careful when toasting pine nuts, they will burn readily</p>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F). </p>
<p>Place chestnuts and stock in a small saucepan over medium heat and simmer until the chestnuts are tender but not mushy, 5-10 minutes. Add the parsley and pine nuts and mix to combine.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, brush a baking dish (large enough to hold all the mushrooms and chestnuts) lightly with olive oil, and spread mushrooms over the base. Season with salt and pepper (if your stock is quite salty, only use pepper here. Spoon chestnuts and their cooking liquid over the top. Sprinkle with parmesan.</p>
<p>Bake in the oven until parmesan has melted and mushrooms have cooked, about half an hour. If the parmesan starts to brown before the mushrooms are cooked, cover dish with a sheet of alfoil, pricked in a couple of places to let the steam out. Serve immediately.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fried halloumi with caremalised fennel</title>
		<link>/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 14:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here's one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn't tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/caremalisedfennelhalloumi2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here&#8217;s one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn&#8217;t tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>
<p>Store bought halloumi will work just fine here, but if you&#8217;d like to have a go at making it yourself, the recipe I followed (which worked really well) can be found <a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/Halloumi.html" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;I ordered my cheese making supplies from <a href="http://www.greenlivingaustralia.com.au/" target="_blank">Green Living Australia</a> in Queensland who had fantastically speedy service. Making halloumi requires some patience, but the product is well worth it and it&#8217;s so satisfying to convert a big pot of milk into a tasty block of cheese oneself.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large bulb fennel, trimmed, quartered and cut into 5-10mm thick slices</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil, plus a little extra</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon caraway seeds, toasted and ground</li>
<li>pinch fennel seeds, toasted and ground (just add to the caraway and prepare together)</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried tarragon</li>
<li>1/4 cup white wine (optional)</li>
<li>1/4 cup loosely packed fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
<li>100g halloumi cheese, cut into 5mm thick slices</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat 2 tablespoons olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the fennel, ground spices and tarragon and cook until fennel begins to soften. Add the wine (if using, otherwise just keep cooking as is) and cook until pan is almost dry and fennel is tender and golden. If the pan dries out and fennel browns before cooking through, add a little water.</p>
<p>Transfer fennel to a bowl and toss with lemon juice and fresh herbs.</p>
<p>Rinse out the pan before cooking the halloumi. Unless using a non-stick pan, or if the teflon coating is starting to go, add a little oil to coat the pan. You don&#8217;t need much oil as the halloumi will release its own fat as it cooks. Turn the heat up to high and when the pan is nice and hot add the halloumi slices. Don&#8217;t add the halloumi while the pan is still cool or it will melt into a blob before a nice crust forms. Fry halloumi until light golden on the underside then flip and cook until both sides are light golden. This will only take around 1-2 minutes per side.</p>
<p>Arrange the fennel on plates and serve the fried halloumi atop the fennel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green smoothie</title>
		<link>/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 11:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/28/2013-4-28-green-smoothie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​This smoothie really does taste better than anything its colour ought. It's sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Greensmoothie2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This smoothie really does taste much better than anything its colour ought. It&#8217;s sweet, refreshing and nutritious all at the same time. I mean really, how can something so green not be good for you?!</p>
<p>This recipe is based on one by <a href="http://theshiksa.com/2013/04/03/green-smoothie/" target="_blank">one by The Shiksa</a>. The slight graininess in the texture comes from the chia seeds; if you don&#8217;t like it cut down the chia or try soaking the seeds it in advance. If you want to soak the chia seeds, just pour a little hot water over them and stir, allow to sit for an hour or two then add the seeds and their soaking water to the smoothie.</p>
<p>When making this, don&#8217;t throw everything in the blender at once or you&#8217;ll end up with chunks in your smoothie. Add the fruit and kale one handful at a time and you&#8217;ll get much better results.</p>
<p>Makes around 1.4L which is enough for about 4 normal glasses, but I split this into two 750mL bottles and take one into work each day.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 1/2 cups cold water</li>
<li>1 pear, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1 granny smith apple, cored and chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup green grapes</li>
<li>2 tablespoons chia seeds</li>
<li>1 cup, loosely packed, fresh mint leaves</li>
<li>1/2 bunch (2-3 cups) kale, coarsely chopped</li>
<li>juice of 1 lime, about 2 tablespoons</li>
<li>1 teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>8 or more ice cubes, depending on how cold you&#8217;d like it</li>
</ul>
<p>Place the water in a blender and add one handful of the pear/apple. Blend until smooth. Continue adding the pear and apple, a handful at a time, blending between each handful. Add the grapes and blend until smooth. Add the chia seeds, blend until smooth. Add the mint, blend again. Add the kale, again only a handful at a time, blending between each batch. Add the lime juice and cinnamon and blend until well mixed. Add the ice-cubes, blend until crushed and enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pumpkin quinoa porridge</title>
		<link>/2013/04/22/2013-4-22-pumpkin-quinoa-porridge/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 14:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/22/2013-4-22-pumpkin-quinoa-porridge/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Being a porridge, this is a lovely warm and sweet breakfast or brunch dish, but I did have it for dinner the other night when I was feeling in need of something cosy. I'd had a nap in the afternoon and woke up feeling more groggy than refreshed and thinking that if I was going to cook dinner it had better be particularly comforting and not too involved. So, I made this pumpkin quinoa porridge, and it has rapidly become a regular at my table.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/pumpkinquinoaporridge.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Being a porridge, this is a lovely warm and sweet breakfast or brunch dish, but I did have it for dinner the other night when I was feeling in need of something cosy. I&#8217;d had a nap in the afternoon and woke up feeling more groggy than refreshed and thinking that if I was going to cook dinner it had better be particularly comforting and not too involved. So, I made this pumpkin quinoa porridge, and it has rapidly become a regular at my table.</p>
</p>
<p>The recipe is based on one from the&nbsp;<a href="http://withfoodandlove.com/breakfast-brunch/first-of-fall/" target="_blank">With Food + Love</a>&nbsp;blog by Sherrie Castellano.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The pumpkin puree and quinoa can be cooked in larger batches in advance and kept in the fridge for a few days, making it super quick and easy to throw this together for breakfast on a chilly morning.</p>
<p>For a dairy/lactose-free version, use soy or other non-dairy milk. For a vegan alternative, use a non-dairy milk and replace the honey with agave nectar or maple syrup.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1/3 cup quinoa (makes about 1 cup when cooked)</li>
<li>1cm piece cinnamon stick</li>
<li>1 cardamon pod</li>
<li>2 cloves</li>
<li>1 pear or granny smith apple, cored and cut into 1-2cm cubes</li>
<li>2/3 cup <a href="http://freshanddelish.com/recipes/2013/4/22/pumpkin-quinoa-porridge#pumpkinpuree">pumpkin puree (recipe below)</a></li>
<li>1/2 cup milk</li>
<li>1/3 cup sultanas</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon vanilla extract (or seeds scraped from 1/4 vanilla pod)</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon</li>
<li>a few pinches ground nutmeg</li>
<li>1 teaspoon honey</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine quinoa, cinnamon stick, cardamon and cloves with 2/3 cup boiling water in a saucepan over medium-low heat. Simmer until quinoa is tender and water absorbed, 15-20 minutes. Add a little extra water if needed while cooking. Once quinoa is cooked, remove from stove and fish out the spices.</p>
<p>Place pear or apple in a small microwave safe bowl, and add enough boiling water to barely cover the fruit. Microwave for 3-5 minutes until tender, then drain. A ripe pear will be done in 3 minutes, while a firmer pear or an apple will need 4-5 minutes.</p>
<p>Add pear or apple, pumpkin puree, milk, sultanas, vanilla, ground spices and honey to the quinoa. Add a little extra milk if needed. Return to the stove and cook over medium heat, stirring&nbsp;occasionally, until hot. Adjust spices and honey to taste and serve immediately.</p>
<p><a name="pumpkinpuree"></a></p>
<h3>Pumpkin puree</h3>
<p>Quantity will depend very much on the size of your pumpkin. Many recipes will only call for a small fraction-of-a-pumpkin-worth of puree, but I usually cook half or the whole pumpkin and keep the extra on hand in the fridge. I&#8217;ve suggested two methods for cooking the pumpkin below: boiling/steaming requires more &#8216;hands-on&#8217; time, but will cook the pumpkin more quickly; roasting the pumpkin will take an hour or two, but it only needs about 5 minutes of your time, so you can do something else while the pumpkin&#8217;s cooking. Personally I prefer roasting, it just means being a bit organised.</p>
<ul>
<li>1 butternut pumpkin</li>
<li>olive oil (if roasting)</li>
</ul>
<p>Cook the pumpkin:</p>
<p>To boil/steam: Peel and seed pumpkin and cut into 2cm cubes. Boil or steam until pumpkin is very tender, then drain.</p>
<p>To roast: Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F). Cut pumpkin in half lengthwise and scoop out the seeds. Brush cut sides lightly with olive oil. Place, cut sides down, on a baking tray and roast until pumpkin is very soft. This will take about 1.5 hours although cooking time will vary depending on the size of your pumpkin. You can test if the pumpkin is cooked through using a skewer. Peel the skin away from the pumpkin (or if it&#8217;s not coming away easily, turn pumpkin halves over and scoop out the flesh).</p>
<p>Puree the pumpkin flesh either with a potato masher/fork or in a food processor. In the case of the latter, it&#8217;s generally a good idea to allow the pumpkin to cool slightly before processing. Using a food processor will give you a smooth puree, while mashing by hand will result in a &#8216;chunkier&#8217; consistency.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lemon scented silverbeet with currants</title>
		<link>/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 12:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/18/2013-4-18-lemon-scented-silverbeet-with-currants/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.​</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/silverbeetlemoncurrants2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This is a simple and effective way of livening up a humble plate of silverbeet. The mellow fruitiness of the olive oil is brightened by the lemon juice, and the currants add little bursts of sweetness to each mouthful.</p>
<p>Serves 2-3 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>1 bunch silverbeet, rinsed, stems removed and coarsely chopped</li>
<li>1 1/2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
<li>2 tablespoons currants</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add silverbeet and lemon juice and toss to coat silverbeet with the lemon and oil. I like to add the currants now too, as cooking them with the silverbeet will make them nice and juicy. Cook, stirring frequently, until silverbeet is just wilted, about 5 minutes. Serve immediately.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Broccoli salad</title>
		<link>/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/15/2013-4-15-broccoli-salad/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn't like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/broccolisaladeditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made mayonnaise on the weekend to serve with a baked snapper, and had some left over. Pondering what to do with it, I remembered this unusual broccoli salad, which is an interesting mix of a creamy dressing, sweet cranberries and of course nice healthy broccoli. If you have someone who doesn&#8217;t like their greens, perhaps give this one a try.</p>
<p>Despite the broccoli, this is actually quite a sweet salad, so keep this in mind when thinking about what to pair it with (perhaps a quiche or grilled fish).</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, just skip the almonds.</p>
<p>Serves 4 as a side</p>
<ul>
<li>2 heads broccoli, stems and florets, chopped into bite-size pieces</li>
<li>1/2 cup mayonnaise*</li>
<li>1 scant tablespoon red wine vinegar</li>
<li>2 teaspoons honey</li>
<li>1/4 red onion, finely chopped</li>
<li>1/2 cup dried cranberries</li>
<li>1/2 cup flaked or slivered almonds, toasted</li>
</ul>
<p>*On this occasion I used homemade mayonnaise, which was delicious, but I have made this with store-bought before and that works too. This was my first time making mayonnaise so I haven&#8217;t developed my own version yet, but if you&#8217;re interested, the recipe I followed can be found <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/wordofmouth/2010/jul/01/how-to-make-perfect-mayonnaise" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Steam the broccoli until just tender, you want it to retain some crispness so try and avoid over-cooking. The stems will take a little longer to cook, so I generally start steaming these first, then after a few minutes add the florets and steam for another couple of minutes. When cooked, swirl the broccoli in icy water to chill. This will both stop the cooking and chill it for the salad. Drain and pat dry.</p>
<p>To make the dressing, mix mayonnaise, vinegar and honey together in a small bowl.</p>
<p>Combine broccoli, onion and cranberries. Pour in dressing and toss to coat. Sprinkle the almonds over the top just before serving. (The cranberries and onion have a habit of accumulating in the bottom of a large salad bowl, so take note to scoop these up as you&#8217;re serving the broccoli.)</p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
