<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Appetisers &#8211; Fresh and delish</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/appetisers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Delicious and healthy gluten-free vegetarian and fish recipes</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 06:51:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Stuffed capsicums with parsley pesto</title>
		<link>/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 04:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy/lactose-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2014/08/16/2014-7-27-stuffed-capsicums-with-parsley-pesto/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:15px">It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner's been asking as he shares his suspicions that I'm trying to poison him with the herb, we've been eating that much of it lately! No, I don't have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden.&#160;</span></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Stuffedcapsicum2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>It is possible to overdose on parsley? This is the question my partner&#8217;s been asking as he shares his suspicions that I&#8217;m trying to poison him with the herb, we&#8217;ve been eating that much of it lately! No, I don&#8217;t have a weird parsley obsession or craving (and I most certainly am not trying to poison anyone), we just have two parsley plants that are on a mission to take over the world, starting with our veggie garden. In a battle that&#8217;s been ongoing for several months now, I&#8217;m starting to get the upper hand, in large part thanks to regular batches of <a href="#parsleypesto">parsley pesto</a>.</p>
<p>I was quite proud of these <a href="#stuffedcapsicums">stuffed capsicums</a> because they centred around ingredients picked fresh from our garden: the parsley, of course, and also the sage and this delightful harvest of capsicums:</p>
<p>      <img src="/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Capsicumparselyharvest1editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>Enjoy these stuffed capsicums by themselves or pair with a dose of protein, perhaps eggs or baked fish, for a complete meal.&nbsp;If you&#8217;re entertaining, the capsicums can be prepared and stuffed in advance. Store them in the fridge in an airtight container. Take them out an hour or so before baking so they can come to room temperature, or allow a bit of extra baking time if they&#8217;re still cold.</p>
<p>For a nut-free version, omit the walnuts when making the pesto. For a vegan or dairy free version, the pesto is still very good without the parmesan (and I&#8217;ll sometimes make it without cheese if we&#8217;ve run out at home).</p>
<h3 id="stuffedcapsicums">Stuffed Capsicums</h3>
<p>Serves 4 as a side or light meal</p>
<ul>
<li>4 capsicums</li>
<li>⅓ cup brown rice</li>
<li>1 brown onion, diced</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, finely diced or chopped</li>
<li>6 leaves fresh sage, finely chopped</li>
<li>¼ cup currants</li>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>⅓ cup <a href="#parsleypesto">parsley pesto (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F). Brush a baking dish large enough to hold all the capsicums lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Add the brown rice and ¾ cup water to a saucepan and bring to the boil over a medium heat. Reduce heat to low and simmer until water is absorbed and rice tender, adding a little more water during cooking if needed.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, behead the capsicums (i.e. slice the tops off so you have the capsicum with a &#8216;lid&#8217;). Use a spoon to scoop out the seeds; rinsing under running water can also help clear away loose seeds. Set aside for later use.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon olive oil in a frying pay over medium head and add the onion. Cook, stirring frequently, until onion softens. Add the garlic and sage and cook for another minute or two.</p>
<p>In a bowl stir together the onion mixture, rice, currants, and parsley pesto. Taste and season with salt and pepper to taste.</p>
<p>Spoon stuffing into the capsicums and top with the lids. If you have left over filling it makes a tasty snack or part of lunch the next day. Arrange capsicums in the baking dish and bake until capsicums are cooked and stuffing is heated through, about 30 minutes. Enjoy!</p>
<h3 id="parsleypesto">Parsley Pesto</h3>
<p>Makes about 3/4 cup</p>
<ul>
<li>large bunch flat-leaf parsley</li>
<li>1/4 cup walnuts, toasted</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic, unpeeled</li>
<li>3-6 tablespoons olive oil (exact quantity will depend on how much parsley you have and on the blender you&#8217;re using).</li>
<li>salt</li>
<li>pepper</li>
<li>1/4 cup grated parmesan</li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350F) and roast garlic for about 20 minutes, until tender.</p>
<p>Add parsley and 2-3 tablespoons of olive oil to a blender or small food processor (I&#8217;ve found my stick blender works best). Process until finely chopped and if parsley does not blend well add more oil. You may also need to stop the blender and scrape down the sides.</p>
<p>Peel the garlic and add it, the walnuts and a pinch each of salt and pepper. Process until you have a paste-like consistency.</p>
<p>Add the parmesan and process briefly to combine. Taste and adjust seasoning as needed.</p>
<p>This will keep stored in the fridge for about a week. The colour may darken a little but it still tastes just as good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spanakopita filled chickpea crepes</title>
		<link>/2013/05/08/2013-4-30-spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 14:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/05/08/2013-4-30-spanakopita-filled-chickpea-crepes/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This came about from my unwillingness to give up ​my favourite Spanakopita filling from my pre-coeliac-diagnosis days. Spanakopita is a Greek spinach and cheese pie. Here, I've taken the same spinach and cheese mix, rolled it up in chickpea crepes and topped with tomato sauce.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/spanakopitachickpeacrepeseditedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>This came about from my unwillingness to give up my favourite Spanakopita filling from my pre-coeliac-diagnosis days. Spanakopita is a Greek spinach and cheese pie. Here, I&#8217;ve taken the same spinach and cheese mix, rolled it up in chickpea crepes and topped with tomato sauce.</p>
<p>I used to make this with buckwheat crepes and ended up making chickpea crepes this time somewhat by accident. Well almost &#8211; I didn&#8217;t misread the label on the flour I was using, but I did forget to check the supplies in my pantry before doing the shopping. It turned out to be somewhat serendipitous as&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 1.6em;">I think the chickpea flour actually results in a much better texture.</span></p>
<p>For a nut-free version, skip the pine nuts.</p>
<p>Serves 3-4 as a main or 6 as a starter</p>
<ul>
<li>olive oil</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 onion, finely diced</span></li>
<li>1 large bunch spinach or silverbeet, stems&nbsp;<span style="line-height: 1.6em;">removed and finely chopped</span></li>
<li>2 eggs, lightly whisked</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">300g ricotta</span></li>
<li>120g fetta</li>
<li>1/4 cup fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>2 tablespoons fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>a few pinches ground nutmeg</li>
<li>a few pinches pepper</li>
<li>1 cup freshly grated parmesan, plus extra to serve</li>
<li>1/4 cup pine nuts, lightly toasted (be careful, they burn easily)</li>
<li><a href="#chickpeacrepes">chickpea crepes (recipe below)</a></li>
<li><a href="#tomatosauce">tomato sauce (recipe below)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Preheat oven to 180˚C (350 F). Brush a baking dish (about 20cm x 30cm) lightly with olive oil.</p>
<p>Heat 1 tablespoon oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add onion and cook until tender, about 10 minutes. Add spinach and cook until just wilted. Transfer onion and spinach to a colander and allow to drain and cool.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, mix together eggs, cheeses, herbs and spices. Stir in the cooled spinach mixture.</p>
<p>Spread a chickpea crepe flat and spoon 3-4 tablespoons<span>&nbsp;</span><span>(about 1/6 of the total filling, depending on how many crepes you have)&nbsp;</span><span>of the mixture in a line down the middle. Sprinkle 1-2 teaspoons pine nuts over the top. Fold one side of the crepe over the filling, and roll towards the other side until you have a nice roll. Place roll in the baking dish with the &#8216;loose&#8217; side down to hold the roll closed. Repeat with remaining crepes.</span></p>
<p>Bake in the oven until filling has cooked through, about 40 minutes. If crepes are starting to brown (check after about 20 minutes), cover the dish with a sheet of alfoil, pricked in a couple of places to let steam escape.</p>
<p>Serve with tomato sauce spooned over the top and sprinkled with parmesan cheese.</p>
<h3 id="chickpeacrepes">Chickpea crepes</h3>
<p>For dairy/lactose-free crepes, use a non-dairy milk such as soy.</p>
<p>Makes about 6 20cm crepes</p>
<ul>
<li>1 cup chickpea flour</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">pinch salt</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 egg, lightly beaten</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">3/4 cup milk</span></li>
<li>canola oil</li>
</ul>
<p>Combine flour and salt in a mixing bowl. In a smaller bowl, whisk together egg and milk. Add the liquids to the dry ingredients and whisk well until you have a smooth batter.</p>
<p>Heat a non-stick frying pan over a medium-high heat and add about 1 tablespoon oil to coat. Add about 1/2 cup (I use one ladle-full) of batter to the pan and swirl pan so batter spreads out to form a thin layer. For the spanakopita filled chickpea crepes, you want your crepes quite thin so you can roll them up; if the mixture isn&#8217;t spreading out enough you can thin the batter by adding a little more milk. Cook until top has just set and underside is golden. This will only take a minute or two once your pan is hot. Flip and cook for another minute or so until golden on both sides. Set aside, atop some paper towel to drain any excess oil. Repeat until all batter is cooked, adding a little oil between crepes if needed.</p>
<h3 id="tomatosauce">Tomato sauce</h3>
<p>Makes 2-3 cups</p>
<ul>
<li>1 tablespoon olive oil</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1 onion, finely diced</span></li>
<li>3 cloves garlic, finely diced or crushed</li>
<li>1 teaspoon dried oregano*</li>
<li>1/4 cup red wine (optional)</li>
<li>1 kg tomatoes, peeled, seeded and chopped**</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">1/2 cup fresh basil, finely diced*</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">salt</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">pepper</span></li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.6em;"></span><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">sugar (optional, if needed)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.6em;">*Use fresh or dried herbs, depending on what&#8217;s on hand. Just adjust the quantities (you&#8217;ll need less dried than fresh) and add dried herbs earlier on in the cooking than fresh.</span></p>
<p><span>**The Former Chef blog provides a good se</span><span>t of instructions on&nbsp;</span><a href="http://www.formerchef.com/2009/08/20/how-to-peel-and-seed-fresh-tomatoes/">How to Peel and Seed Tomatoes</a><span>.</span></p>
<p>Heat olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add onion and saute until tender, about 10 minutes. Add garlic and dried herbs and cook for another minute or two until fragrant. If using wine, add this now and cook until pan is almost dry (otherwise go straight to the next step).</p>
<p>Add the tomatoes and cook until sauce has thickened. I find this can take up to about half an hour. 5-10 minutes before sauce is ready, stir in the fresh herbs. Add a few pinches each of salt and pepper, to taste. Taste the sauce and if it is tart add a little sugar &#8211; only about 1/4-1/2 teaspoon to start, then adjust as needed. If you accidentally make your sauce too sweet you can balance it out with a little lemon juice.</p>
<p>You can serve this sauce immediately, or keep it in the fridge for a few days.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fried halloumi with caremalised fennel</title>
		<link>/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 04:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetisers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nut-free friendly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quick & easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2013/04/29/2013-4-28-fried-halloumi-with-caramelised-fennel/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>​I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here's one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn't tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/caremalisedfennelhalloumi2editedresized.jpg" alt=""/></p>
<p>I made halloumi from scratch for the first time last weekend! And it worked! Here&#8217;s one of my subsequent creations which I served up for a friend the other night. She hadn&#8217;t tried halloumi or fennel before, and I think I sold her on both accounts with this dish.</p>
<p>Store bought halloumi will work just fine here, but if you&#8217;d like to have a go at making it yourself, the recipe I followed (which worked really well) can be found <a href="http://www.cheesemaking.com/Halloumi.html" target="_blank">here</a>.&nbsp;I ordered my cheese making supplies from <a href="http://www.greenlivingaustralia.com.au/" target="_blank">Green Living Australia</a> in Queensland who had fantastically speedy service. Making halloumi requires some patience, but the product is well worth it and it&#8217;s so satisfying to convert a big pot of milk into a tasty block of cheese oneself.</p>
<p>Serves 2</p>
<ul>
<li>1 large bulb fennel, trimmed, quartered and cut into 5-10mm thick slices</li>
<li>2 tablespoons olive oil, plus a little extra</li>
<li>1/2 teaspoon caraway seeds, toasted and ground</li>
<li>pinch fennel seeds, toasted and ground (just add to the caraway and prepare together)</li>
<li>1/4 teaspoon dried tarragon</li>
<li>1/4 cup white wine (optional)</li>
<li>1/4 cup loosely packed fresh parsley, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 tablespoon fresh mint, finely chopped</li>
<li>1 teaspoon lemon juice</li>
<li>100g halloumi cheese, cut into 5mm thick slices</li>
</ul>
<p>Heat 2 tablespoons olive oil in a frying pan over medium heat. Add the fennel, ground spices and tarragon and cook until fennel begins to soften. Add the wine (if using, otherwise just keep cooking as is) and cook until pan is almost dry and fennel is tender and golden. If the pan dries out and fennel browns before cooking through, add a little water.</p>
<p>Transfer fennel to a bowl and toss with lemon juice and fresh herbs.</p>
<p>Rinse out the pan before cooking the halloumi. Unless using a non-stick pan, or if the teflon coating is starting to go, add a little oil to coat the pan. You don&#8217;t need much oil as the halloumi will release its own fat as it cooks. Turn the heat up to high and when the pan is nice and hot add the halloumi slices. Don&#8217;t add the halloumi while the pan is still cool or it will melt into a blob before a nice crust forms. Fry halloumi until light golden on the underside then flip and cook until both sides are light golden. This will only take around 1-2 minutes per side.</p>
<p>Arrange the fennel on plates and serve the fried halloumi atop the fennel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
